- Gotcha!
Summer. It's the season of love.
Stop it!
Is burning a young lady's bare body
the sun's mischief?
Is the quivering of asphalt
a heat haze mirage?
A boy and girl
bare their hearts to each other
and are invited to take the next step
in a male-female relationship.
The curtain comes up
on a summer vacation like that.
Half a month has passed!
During that time,
nothing in particular has happened.
AUGUST
I screwed up.
I totally screwed up.
SHOPPING
FIREWORKS FESTIVAL
Was that a sigh?
If you sigh like that,
happiness will flee in all directions.
AI HAYASAKA
WANTS TO GET SOAKED
President Shirogane
says he's at home right now,
so if you loiter around outside,
you may see him.
Don't talk silly, Hayasaka.
As if I would engage in stalker-like—
He says he's at home?
Hayasaka, since when have you been
in contact with the president?
Oh, I'm not.
He was grumbling about it on Twitter.
Twitter?
What's that? No, I've heard of it!
Twitter...
I think Miss Fujiwara does it.
DICTIONARY
Twitter... Twitter...
Well, I'm going to take a bath.
RESERVED
Again?
FEMALE EMPLOYEES'
BATHROOM
She gets to do that?
There.
SPLASH
FSSS
Hayasaka! Come quick!
Wh-What is it?
The Internet is broken!
It must be the major incident
of the century.
So, I tried to start doing that thing,
you know, Twitter...
USER NAME
EMAIL ADDRESS
I AGREE TO THE TERMS
OF SERVICE.
but the letters are garbled!
The letters are not garbled.
Password.
Can I use my bank password?
No.
Hopeless at I.T.
HOPELESS AT I.T.
When it comes to technology,
Kaguya prefers to be analog.
She can do mental arithmetic,
but cant use a calculator.
When she looks into something, she'll use
a map or encyclopedia instead of googling.
ENCYCLOPEDIA
She does use the Internet once in a while
to check the weather or news headlines,
but never leaves the confines
of the search engine site's top page.
She's about as tech-savvy as the old man
who runs the candy shop.
YAMADA STORE
Like this?
Yes. Now you have an account,
Lady Kaguya.
MIYUKI SHIROGANE
CHIKA FUJIWARA
YU ISHIGAMI
I printed out the accounts
of the other student council members.
For example,
this is the secretary's account.
I WENT TO DUBAI
I WENT TO CALIFORNIA
She clearly spends a great deal of time
tweeting and no time at all studying.
I WENT TO BALI
I WENT TO HAWAII
All she does is travel abroad.
And this anime icon is the treasur—
Not interested.
The best thing to do is play around
with it until you're used to it.
Okay.
Well, I'm going back to my bath.
This job is exhausting.
The only way I can take it
is by washing my fatigue away like this.
Lady Kaguya doesn't understand.
She should appreciate me more.
Hayasaka! Come quick!
Jeez.
Lady Kaguya,
would you stop barging in on—
I've been banned from Twitter!
I'm surprised you even know
about being banned.
THIS ACCOUNT'S TWEETS
ARE PROTECTED.
L-Look!
I can't see it! Why?
Did I do something wrong?
President Shirogane
has a protected account.
Protected?
It's because some trolls will flame you
no matter what you post.
This goes to show that the president
is on his toes about privacy.
My main account is protected, too.
You'd better be very careful, too,
Lady Kaguya.
In other words,
think of your account as your house.
With normal accounts,
the front door is wide open,
so visitors can come and go
as they please.
But cautious people
keep their front door locked,
and only visitors
who are given a key can come in.
Then, where do you get a key?
That's simple.
FOLLOW
LIKES
If you click this "Follow" button,
a request for approval
will be sent to President Shirogane.
If he agrees,
you'll then be able to see his tweets.
I imagine he'd okay any request, as long as
their profile shows they go to Shuchiin.
But... But I... But I...
There's no way I can do that!
After all, it would mean...
President! Please open up!
I want to know more about you!
REQUESTING APPROVAL
FOR A FOLLOW
I want to know what you think about
and what you usually do!
BAM BAM
You want to know about me that badly?
You're that interested
in my 140-character monologues?
That's cute.
APPROVED
Like that, right?
Is this a new kind of stupidity?
You really think
of the most useless things.
Are you mad at me, Hayasaka?
Mad? More like I'm wondering...
how long you're going to make me
stand around half-naked.
Sorry.
If you won't do it, Lady Kaguya, I—
Wait! Wait!
Hold on!
I'll do it when I'm good and ready!
FOLLOW
LIKES
I wonder what the president
tweets about.
What is he doing? What does he like?
How is he spending his summer?
But...
That's it! I'll protect my account, too!
- Then, if the president follows me—
- Wake up and smell the coffee.
You've never succeeded
with that pattern before. Not even once.
In the end,
she wasn't able to send the request.
Lady Kaguya is stubborn to a fault.
They both are hopeless.
If either were open about their feelings,
they could both be happy.
But I envy them.
I wish I loved someone like that.
As if...
Hayasaka! Come quick!
Results of today's match...
None.
KAGUYA AND SHIROGANE DIDN'T MEET UP
Please! Enough already!
CLICK CLICK
HER TYPING IS VERY FAST
CHIKA FUJIWARA
REALLY WANTS TO EAT IT
Japan!
I loved Egypt.
I wish we could've stayed there
a little longer.
The ta'amiya and kushari were delicious!
You're just thinking about food!
Maybe you wanted to stay longer, Sis,
but I couldn't wait to get back to Japan!
Why?
After all...
My name is Saburo Odajima.
I'm an insignificant middle manager.
RAMEN
HAKATA TENRYU
My hobby is frequenting ramen shops.
TENRYU RAMEN
Welcome.
I came to a neighborhood shop today.
The most popular item on the menu
is pork bone broth ramen...
but that's not for me.
I get the inconspicuous one
all the way at the end.
Soy sauce pork bone. Thin.
How about the noodles?
Firm.
That is this shop's optimum combination.
The way I ordered
shows I'm in the know.
Welcome.
It smells wonderful!
GLOW
Well, well, a cute customer...
Maybe she wandered in
thinking this was a cake shop.
What can I get you?
Um,
soy sauce pork bone ramen, thin broth!
Impossible!
Did a girl like this suddenly calculate
this shop's optimum combination?
OPTIMUM COMBINATION
Is it a coincidence? No.
This isn't the kind of shop a young woman
would enter alone this late at night.
RAMEN
Could this woman be one of "my people"?
MY PEOPLE
What about the noodles?
Um,
super-firm!
FSSS
Super-firm?
Like a sheep,
she chose the fad level of firmness.
She's just an average girl after all.
I worried for nothing.
I overestimated her.
Here you go.
All right, then. I'll teach this girl
the real way to eat ramen.
First, you note the scent
of the soup itself.
The idea is to appreciate
each scent in turn
starting from the fragrant
red pickled ginger.
Of course, the owner is fully aware of that.
I'm delighted at his consideration,
placing the ginger farthest away.
Next, the taste.
Letting the air mix in while you taste it.
I use my brain completely,
sharpening my senses of smell and taste.
And then, the noodles.
I bite off a small amount,
as if making sure of the flavor,
and enjoy it as it slides down.
Here you go.
Thank you for the meal!
Finally, the chaser.
In order to enjoy the delicate flavors,
I drink water to wash away the soy and salt
on my tongue, resetting my palate.
This makes all the difference.
This is one set.
Repeating the set over and over
is what we call the "water cycle."
Now, what about you, young lady?
Mini-ramen?
Little bits. Little bits. Little bits.
She really is just an ordinary girl.
GOBBLE...
Looks like she's enjoying it.
Well, I can't really look down on her.
Mini-ramen,
where you eat it all in each bite,
is the ultimate form
of the "one is all" philosophy after all.
Little bits. Little bits. Little bits.
Little bits! Little bits. Little bits!
But by taking little bites like that,
the noodles will stretch out and swell up.
Swell up?
Super-firm! Super-firm! Super-firm!
Is that why she said, "Super-firm"?
Did this girl calculate
that the noodles would stretch out?
Slurp, slurp, slurp!
Moreover, using that small utensil
is perfect for mini-ramen!
It can't be!
If this was all calculated...
The metro's four ramen kings...
Jinbocho's Mashimashi Mama,
the Hermit of Sugamo,
even J. Suzuki of Koenji...
THE METRO AREA'S
BIG FOUR RAMEN KINGS
JINBOCHO'S
MASHIMASHI MAMA
J. SUZUKI OF KOENJI
HERMIT OF SUGAMO
So, she possesses the sense
of situational assessment
equivalent to the monsters
of the ramen world!
SAN OF SHIBUYA
Not yet.
That's right. She's not there yet.
It's kind of sad.
It's the wall that can't be overcome,
and it's owing to being a woman.
- Garlic!
Unfortunately, avoiding that scent
pegs her as a wannabe ramen connoisseur.
She's a fake!
Looks like she finished
eating the ingredients.
What is she gonna do now?
There's no more to spoon out!
What's she gonna do?
Is she gonna go for it?
She's gonna go for it?
CRUNCH
She went for it!
She overcame the wall of womanhood!
I have to give her props!
She's earned my respect!
She's definitely "my people"!
A ramen connoisseur!
Don't tell me!
Even the soup?
Too much salt!
You're drinking garlic, too!
But...
It looks delicious!
...there was a time in my life, too!
Thank you for the meal!
When did I become such an old man?
GULP GULP
That's it! Run!
That youth is the radiance I lost!
I'm young and starving!
Keep running!
AHHH
POLISHED IT OFF
Thank you!
Boom!
You...
COOL
Result of today's ramen match...
RESULT OF TODAY'S RAMEN MATCH:
Fujiwara wins.
FUJIWARA WINS
WHERE IS YOUR SWITCH?
My ramen switch is on!
MIYUKI SHIROGANE
WANTS TO SEE YOU
Since summer vacation began,
three weeks have passed.
Nothing of note
has happened during that time.
Days of studying, working, eating,
taking a bath, sleeping, and that's all.
This has become
a boring summer vacation.
The festival at the end of vacation
is the only plan
he and Kaguya made to see each other.
Other than that,
they haven't exchanged a single text,
let alone go out together.
The high hurdle of asking the other person
to go out and do something fun
is still insurmountable.
It wasn't supposed to be like this.
I wonder what Shinomiya's doing now.
Why has it come to this?
The reason, Lady Kaguya...
is that, all your plans are based on the premise
that the president is going to invite you.
SUMMER VACATION PLANS
FOR KAGUYA
You've been too naive.
Hayasaka, why are you looking
at your lady's notebook
so brazenly and without permission?
Why don't you just ask him
to do something?
Don't be ridiculous!
It'd look like I wanted to do something
for fun with the president!
That's exactly right.
I mean, you're not even refuting me.
TO: KAGUYA SHINOMIYA
Shi-no-mi-ya...
What-are-you-doing...
DELETE THIS MAIL?
SAVE
DELETE
Am I some blushing girl?
WHAP
Write, delete, write, delete!
What is this, your first love?
It is his first love.
AUGUST
That's it! I'm done! I'm through!
SUBJECT: OCTOPUS
LOOK! A LIVE OCTOPUS!!
FROM: SHIROGANE
I WAS TRYING TO TELL YOU SOMETHING
AS YOU HUNG UP THE PHONE
LOOKS LIKE TONIGHT WILL GET
PRETTY COLD, SO BE WARM
AND GO TO SLEEP
GOOD NIGHT
No matter how much you read that,
it won't make new messages appear.
Did that message make you so happy
that you've saved it all this time?
The president's first text to you.
You were thrilled when he made
the first move there, weren't you?
You can't forget it, huh?
Get off my back!
I don't think that at all,
so stop trying to analyze my heart!
I'm going out.
Where are you going, Bro?
Grocery shopping for dinner.
In your school uniform?
Well, I may stop at school on the way.
The school isn't on the way.
What I'm doing now doesn't make any sense.
But I thought, "What if," and...
Nice and cool.
I want to see him...
STUDENT COUNCIL ROOM
Well, of course not...
- I wish summer vacation weren't so long.
RESULTS OF TODAY'S MATCH: NONE
BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T MEET UP
I don't have any summer memories.
Look! Look!
But that's not a problem.
I've never gone on a family vacation.
But that's okay...
because everyone treats me
like I'm special.
I've never gone to see
a fireworks display.
But that's all right...
because even the little lights
I see from out my window are pretty.
FROM: MISS FUJIWARA
LET'S MEET UP IN FRONT OF
THE MOAI STATUE TOMORROW!
I CAN'T WAIT!!
I've never gone shopping
with a group of friends.
Yeah. Like this one?
So, I felt a mix
of anxiety and anticipation.
But it would be okay.
The people I was going with
were good people.
They were all very nice.
But it's okay.
I'm used to it.
I can't do what I want in this life.
FROM: KAGUYA
SUBJECT: TOMORROW - I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T GO SHOPPING TOMORROW.
"My father suddenly summoned me
to the main house in Kyoto, so I have to go.
Don't worry about me. All of you
should go on and have fun, okay?"
That's what she says.
What should we do?
In this case...
we put it off!
The whole point
is for all of us to go together.
Good! You're right!
I'll call Kei and let her know.
That's right.
I'm blessed.
I've got friends and a distinguished family
that anyone would envy.
I'm blessed with a resourcefulness
that anyone would be jealous of.
Anyone would conclude that the amount
of my happiness and sorrow are about the same.
So, blessed as I am,
it's only logical that I should suck it up.
F-Father!
Oh, you're here?
Good.
He summoned you
all the way here for that?
Drop dead, asshole.
My father has never said
"good night" to me.
I don't remember him
ever saying "See you later,"
"Good job" or "I love you" to me either.
But it doesn't hurt my feelings.
Because it's always been this way.
By this point, nothing he does
makes me feel one way or the other.
It's okay.
In deference to my family's status,
people around here
behave a certain way toward me...
with great caution...
as if there's no problem...
like I'm a creepy
traditional Japanese doll.
But I don't mind.
After all, I'm going
to a fireworks festival tomorrow.
I CAN'T HEAR
THE FIREWORKS, PART 1