I CAN'T HEAR
THE FIREWORKS, PART 2
Tonight...
Tonight I'm going to a fireworks display!
Even if Miss Fujiwara is a major pain,
for this one night, I'll let it go.
Because she went as far as canceling
a trip so she could go with me.
It really has been
a boring summer vacation.
For the first time, I'll go out with friends.
There's no difference.
My first time
going out with the president.
I won't watch from the window
because I finally get to go see
the huge fireworks up close!
I think that alone is enough for me
to enjoy this whole summer vacation.
See you later.
It really has been
a boring summer vacation.
I'm afraid not.
Lately, your behavior
has been unacceptable, milady.
And with a large crowd,
it would be easy to lose sight of you.
If something happened to you
during that time,
what would I say to your father?
I'm sure he wouldn't care.
I'M SORRY.
I WON'T BE ABLE TO GO TODAY.
I'M REALLY SORRY.
FROM: KAGUYA
SUBJECT: I'M SORRY
"I'm really sorry."
Miss Kaguya.
I want to see everyone.
I wish I'd never known about it.
If I hadn't known,
it would've been a normal summer,
and I wouldn't have suffered like this.
But... But it's okay.
Summer will be over soon.
It's okay.
KAGUYA
I'M A SECOND-YEAR HIGH SCHOOL STUDENT
AT SHUCHIIN ACADEMY.
THANK YOU FOR CHECKING OUT MY PAGE.
KAGUYA / 5 DAYS AGO
THIS IS MY FIRST TWEET.
KAGUYA / RIGHT NOW
I WANT TO SEE THE FIREWORKS WITH EVERYONE.
Roger.
KAGUYA / RIGHT NOW
I WANT TO SEE THE FIREWORKS WITH EVERYONE.
KAGUYA / 5 DAYS AGO
THIS IS MY FIRST TWEET.
Lady Kaguya, how long
do you intend to lie there like that?
This isn't like you.
Normally, by this point, you'd be sneaking
out of the house by hook or by crook.
No matter what I do, it won't work out.
I couldn't go shopping with everyone,
and my father has no interest
in me whatsoever.
The president didn't even send me
a single text this past month.
Nothing at all has worked out for me!
Even if I left the house right now,
it would be meaningless!
I'll never be able to see them again!
No, you'll see them once school starts
whether you like it or not.
Misfortunes never come singly.
When you're dejected,
you really go all out.
Certainly, you've been
through a rough summer.
But maybe not seeing President Shirogane
once over vacation was the best choice
if you think about it
from a long-term perspective.
Time without seeing someone
makes the heart fonder.
I'm sure the president feels
the same way you do right now.
He wants to see you so badly every day.
He counts on his fingers
how many days are left
of summer vacation.
Meanwhile,
if he could somehow meet you
in a date with destiny,
his accumulated desire...
...would be set free all at once?
That's right. There you go.
Now you look like the Lady Kaguya I know.
But two of this house's butlers
are here right now.
There's no way I can escape from here
without any preparation.
Preparation, you say?
WIRELESS
J. SUZUKI OF KOENJI
ONE OF THE METRO AREA'S
BIG FOUR RAMEN KINGS
Take me to Hamamatsucho!
Please!
Lady Kaguya,
dinner is ready.
I'm not hungry.
I'm going to bed.
I'm watching the fireworks.
You don't have a problem
with that, do you?
Very well.
Gotcha.
I get the picture.
Miss Kaguya!
She may be around there.
Please stay here, Fujiwara!
The phone number you have called
is turned off or out of our service area.
It's not going through.
Is it because of the crowd?
Or because my phone is old?
Why?
Young lady, you want to go
see the fireworks, right?
There's a lot of traffic tonight
with all the cars out.
I think you might not make it in time.
I won't make it in time?
After what Hayasaka did for me?
It can't be!
Why won't anything work out for me?
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'll go the rest of the way on foot.
Be careful, young lady.
I will!
We're supposed to meet up
at Takeshiba Wharf.
The main streets are really crowded.
If I run down a backstreet,
I should be able to just make it!
I'm sure I'll meet up with them!
The first younger student I've helped...
The person who became my first friend...
The first person I like...
I'm in that circle of people!
SHOPPING
FIREWORKS FESTIVAL
All summer,
the only thing I've been thinking about
is how happy I would be
if I got to gaze
at those beautiful fireworks
together with my favorite people,
and how wonderful it would be.
God...
this summer,
I don't need love or romance!
So...
So, at least let me be
together with them!
...has concluded.
When you leave,
please pick up your trash,
food and beverages.
Again,
this evening's fireworks display
has concluded.
When you leave,
please pick up your trash,
food and beverages.
Oh, that's right.
There is...
no God.
I wonder if they enjoyed the fireworks.
I hope so.
I only got to see the fireworks
from between the buildings,
but they were so big.
For them, the fireworks
must have looked beautiful.
If everyone else got to enjoy them,
that's enough for me.
I wanted to see them, too!
The fireworks...
With everyone!
Then, I'll show them to you.
President?
Come with me, Shinomiya!
If you wanna see them that badly,
I'll show them to you!
How...
How did you know I was here?
You mean the "Guess Shinomiya's Thoughts
and Search for Her" game?
Compared to the usual,
it was 100 times easier.
Miss Kaguya!
President, I got us a car!
That young lady again!
Everyone hop in!
There!
Driver,
get on the expressway,
and then take the Aqua-Line
towards Umihotaru!
There are fireworks that were postponed
until tonight because of the rain.
President, you mean...
Chiba!
The Kisarazu fireworks display
goes until 8:30!
Can we get to Chiba
in the next 20 minutes?
I don't know!
But it's worth the challenge.
We're gonna show Shinomiya
some fireworks!
I'll step on it, then.
This is just between you and me.
Who is this cool driver?
J. SUZUKI OF KOENJI
ONE OF THE METRO AREA'S
BIG FOUR RAMEN KINGS
God, let us be in time!
President! I can't see anything outside!
The Aqua-Line is an undersea tunnel!
Of course you can't see anything!
A sign for Umihotaru service parking!
We're surfacing!
Let us be in time!
Their focus is on the fireworks.
But I'm sorry.
I can't take my eyes off of...
that face.
The sound of my
heartbeat is so noisy...
...that I can't hear the fireworks.
The first day of the new school term.
Everyone has come back
to their ordinary lives
with melancholy and hope in their hearts
after a long, uneventful summer.
KAGUYA DOESN'T WANT
TO AVOID HIM
One man looks back upon...
TRACING SHIROGANE'S EFFORTS
SAVING A SPOT SIX HOURS
BEFORE THE DISPLAY
GETS THE NEWS THAT SHINOMIYA
CAN'T GO, CALCULATES
HOW SHE REALLY FEELS FROM HER TWEET
RIDES LIKE THE WIND
TO SHINOMIYA'S FAMILY'S HOUSE
USING BINOCULARS OUTSIDE THE HOUSE,
REALIZES SHINOMIYA IS USING
A "BODY DOUBLE" (HAYASAKA),
GOES BACK THE WAY HE CAME AT MACH SPEED
MAKES CALCULATIONS IN HIS HEAD,
FIGURES OUT THE ROUTE SHINOMIYA TOOK,
DETERMINES HER LOCATION
USES THE EVENT INFO
HE HAD INPUT EARLIER,
RIDES LIKE THE WIND
IN A TAXI TO KISARAZU
PAYS THE CAB FARE TO THE TUNE
OF 17,320 YEN (TAKEN FROM
THE POTENTIAL "SHINOMIYA
SUMMER VACATION BUDGET")
USES THE EVENT INFO
HE HAD INPUT EARLIER,
RIDES LIKE THE WIND
IN A TAXI TO KISARAZU
...a memory he made at the end.
Then, I'll show them to you.
Nooo!
And he regrets so much
that he wishes he could die!
You mean the "Guess Shinomiya's Thoughts
and Search for Her" game?
Ow! It hurts!
It hurts so bad!
A dark past!
Summer vacation was all but over,
and Shirogane hadn't seen
Shinomiya even once.
By the day of the fireworks,
Shirogane was so tense
that he couldn't hold it back!
There she is!
That bursting tension caused him
to blurt out a series of cringeworthy lines!
Then, I'll show them to you.
You mean the "Guess Shinomiya's Thoughts
and Search for Her" game?
Compared to the usual,
it was 100 times easier.
I don't know!
But it's worth the challenge.
It's a dark past
that will make him writhe in pain
when he recalls it for the next ten-odd years!
If I saw Shinomiya now...
I don't know what to say,
but the words you said that night...
How can I put it?
I guess you were like on an ego trip.
President...
it was painful.
Somebody, kill me!
Let's have fun this semester, too!
O-Oh, Fujiwara!
Shinomiya, too.
STUDENT COUNCIL ROOM
Hmph.
She won't even look at me!
She views me as someone
who's too pathetic to look at directly!
- Shinomiya, about the other night—
- Hmph.
It's worse than I thought!
Look at all this dust!
She thinks of me as someone
who's too pathetic to even be around!
Wrong! Certainly,
Kaguya is avoiding Shirogane.
But it's definitely not out of any ill will.
In fact, it's just the opposite.
These actions are induced
by bashfulness and nervousness.
Perhaps it might be called
"like-avoidance."
Wh-Why am I avoiding him?
I-It's like I'm self-conscious
around him or something!
HRRRMMM
Talk to him.
Just like you did
before summer vacation.
I have to win Shinomiya's trust back!
Naturally, cheerfully...
I-I'll greet her naturally first!
A straight line linked them
as they moved from opposite directions.
A development that would certainly
make them talk to each other.
However...
Miss Fujiwara,
we need to clean the floor first.
Oh, that's right!
Dusty.
It's hard to strike up a conversation!
I'll clean over here.
They were both back in the saddle,
ready to give it another go!
And yet the result was the same.
No good! The closer I get to the president,
the harder it is to look at him directly!
What kind of expression should I have
when I say something to Shinomiya?
They continued to pass each other by,
just barely missing,
like two aircraft in a dogfight!
But walking by each other twice
is unnatural.
Was it a coincidence?
I see. The president is being shy.
In that case, there's no need
for me to be bashful.
I'm totally calm.
I can do this!
This time, I can go over to him.
I can go over to her!
An asterisk!
Miss Fujiwara,
are you making fun of me?
Keep your mind on the cleaning!
What are the rules of this game?
I have to talk to her
and clear up this misunderstanding!
This time, for sure!
I see! It's not an asterisk!
Hey, what's up?
But it's a triangle!
Now what?
You're mocking me, too, aren't you?
Did I do something?
Jeez, you don't get it at all,
do you, Ishigami?
Why are you suddenly
looking down on me?
Ishigami, am I really
that amusing to you?
You, too, President?
I'm sorry.
This is over my head,
so I'm going home.
Ishigami was shot down.
Poor Ishigami. But four's a crowd.
Three's a crowd, Miss Fujiwara.
Why?
Fujiwara was shot down.
What the hell is going on here?
I know I've been avoiding her,
but Shinomiya has been doing
the same thing, too, repeatedly.
Maybe...
she feels self-conscious!
Calm down, Kaguya!
Close your eyes! It'll be okay!
Maybe she didn't think
I was pathetic but actually cool!
Shirogane was back on his feet!
This time for sure!
This time...
There's something
I really wanted to tell you, President.
President, on the night of the fireworks...
I have to tell him.
I have to say "Thank you"!
Um,
that was painful, huh?
President, on the night of the fireworks...
Painful, painful, painful, painful,
painful, painful, painful, painful...
That was painful, huh?
I-I know, right?
Shirogane was shot down.
President!
There's something I want to tell you!
I-I get it already!
Please wait up, President!
RESULTS OF TODAY'S MATCH:
FLYING ACE SHINOMIYA'S
VICTORY
And so, they were back to normal.
The second semester had begun.
A romantic battle of the brains.
A battle of the sexes in which
neither side can afford to be honest.
With unspoken feelings
hidden in their hearts,
they continue making their wish
for the other person to confess their love.
I swear I'll make you say it.
KAGUYA-SAMA: LOVE IS WAR
You'll say "I love you."