Uniform change!
It has been so humid lately.
Just wearing short sleeves
is so comfortable!
That's true.
CONFESSION
Relationship advice?
Yes.
I don't know what to do.
I heard that the student council
also gives advice on these matters.
I can only rely on you, Ms. Kaguya.
I understand.
Like our President always says,
listening to the worries of students
is the duty of the student council.
Then,
what kind of problem
do you need advice on?
How to break up with
my boyfriend smoothly.
I thought it would be advice on getting
a boyfriend or confessing your love.
Advice on having a boyfriend.
Ms. Kaguya, you are so popular,
-so you must know a lot about dating
-But how can I give advice
-you surely have a good idea!
-when I never dated anyone seriously?
Her expectations are so great.
But I have always taken responsibility
for people,
so I won't ever say I can't do it,
no matter what.
I just have to get through this.
Why do you want to break up?
That is...
because he confessed
his feelings suddenly.
I got caught in the moment and said yes.
but I don't really know him,
and I don't know how to get close to him.
We're even more distanced than before.
I feel bad about it.
So I thought that to break up
would be better than being like this.
That's right.
Until a while ago,
he was just another classmate,
so you don't know what you feel about him.
It's not like you hate him, right?
Of course not.
But I don't know
if this can be called romantic feelings.
First, why don't we start
by knowing his good qualities?
-What do I like about him?
-Yes.
Anybody has good or cute traits.
For example, being earnest,
good at studying,
hardworking,
being truly kind and not abandoning
people when they need help.
Or having a threatening look.
Wouldn't having a threatening look be bad?
No!
I think having a threatening look
can be cute!
You like people
who have a threatening look?
Forget what I just said.
When I think of who has
a threatening look around you...
That's not it.
Let's continue our talk.
You can find one good quality.
Begin thinking, "that's nice!"
Then, you'll start noticing
even more good traits.
By the time you notice it,
you can't take your eyes off him.
When you see them every day,
you'll gradually fall in love with them.
That's what an acquaintance said to me.
I'm not talking about me.
You're not?
This is really not about me.
There is no one that I like.
But what you just said...
I heard what you were talking about.
Fujiwara?
That's so unfair of you
to talk about romance without me.
Leave this kind of talk to me,
Chika, the love detective!
Why are you wheezing?
I was actually listening
to you from the start,
but I dashed to the drama club
and borrowed this costume.
You are worrying because you don't know
if you love your boyfriend.
That was it, right?
Yes.
Then, I would help you find
this lost thing called love!
Then,
try to imagine he is flirting
with someone else.
What are you talking about?
Just try to imagine it.
I feel gloomy.
I am angry. Very angry!
Somehow, you don't feel good.
Right?
In other words, that's jealousy.
You feel bad about it
because you like him.
If you feel bad, it means you love him!
Love?
That's why...
-You also like your boyfriend, Kashiwagi.
-Don't tell me...
-You should cherish that feeling.
-I love him.
I see.
I was thinking that I am a cold person,
not being able to like somebody
who confessed their feelings to me.
But...
That's right!
I really like him!
The situation continues to take shape.
-How can I speak more naturally to him?
-I have to give her accurate advice.
That's right.
How about using
the Romeo and Juliet effect
for cognitive balance?
-Romeo and Juliet?
Romeo and Juliet had obstacles in love
and by having a common
and powerful enemy opposing them,
their love deepened.
A powerful enemy?
It doesn't have to be a person.
It can also be a common imaginary enemy.
I don't know about such an enemy...
No.
There is an enemy
who everybody must stand against!
Who is that?
That is...
the society!
The society?
The never-ending wars,
the constant gap between rich and poor...
-There is no greater enemy!
-But I meant exams or small worries.
I see!
We should both oppose
this corrupt society.
That's quite a big scale problem!
I understand.
We will both start preparing immediately.
-Do your best!
-Wait a little!
Is that all right?
Haven't we created antisocial misfits?
It's all right.
Please contribute to fund-raising
for charity!
Please!
Please contribute to fund-raising
for charity!
Apparently, they were both interested
in charity work from the start.
It seems to have turned
into a good opportunity.
Wishing for peace...
That really is opposing society
in the true sense of the word.
What are you saying?
Her boyfriend is the one who came
to the president for advice.
President?
Shinomiya?
Why are you with them?
Oh, I registered for the fund-raising
as an extracurricular activity.
They don't seem to be doing it
on a whim or as a hobby
and when I see the two of them
unexperienced but fervent,
I can't do much,
but I wanted to support them.
Good grief.
This kind of activity doesn't suit me.
That is what I like about you.
Today's result, Kaguya lost.
PLEASE CONTRIBUTE
TO THE FUND-RAISING FOR CHARITY
PLEASE
Punch it!
I almost hit it!
Unathletic person.
Shirogane excels at studying,
but in regard to all sports,
he is a catastrophe unfit for human eyes.
He delivered newspapers for many years,
worked as a mover in summer,
and he can commute
15 kilometers every day by bicycle.
His physical ability is
by no means reduced.
He is desperately lacking
a sense of coordination.
That is the cause.
For him to maintain
his position at Shuchiin,
he needs an extraordinary amount
of practice every day.
There is a volleyball class next week.
I need to improve until then,
so I can play in front of people.
If I'm like this...
Please take it seriously.
That thing that looks like
a dead alpaca is the president?
Really?
That dead alpaca?
How cute of you.
No way!
Why can't I do it right?
Are you okay, President?
Yes, it's okay...
Secretary Fujiwara?
What are you doing?
I forgot something.
Well...
Did she see me?
Did she see how stupidly I moved around?
No. I'm done.
No more being good in sports and studying.
The brand of "President Shirogane"
who is good at everything.
My image,
that I can do everything perfectly,
without working hard at it.
I didn't really study for the test.
This is bad.
Playing with the ball is fun!
Anyway.
No matter what she thinks,
she can't do that much damage.
The volleyball class will start soon.
I reserved the sports hall
and was practicing.
Somehow my serve is very bad.
Oh, I see.
Would you like me to teach you?
You?
If you want to teach someone
you have to be able to do it yourself.
I can play volleyball at least.
Look!
See?
Amazing!
What a polished serve!
Right?
I didn't know you had such skill!
If I teach you, you would surely get
really good in no time.
President.
What kind of attitude should you have
when asking people to teach you something?
Please, teach me.
Yes, of course.
First, let's find out
what the problems are.
Try to serve a couple of times.
Why does it turn out like that?
I also don't understand.
No matter how often I do it,
my hand clashes against my head.
If I mind my head, I screw up the timing.
It's a complete dead end.
What? Oh, yes.
First, keep your eyes open
when you hit the ball.
Why are you telling me obvious things?
That's right, it's obvious.
So then, open your eyes wide
and hit the ball.
What will that change?
See? It's still no good.
You didn't open them!
You didn't open them.
Why are you saying "it's no use"
when you didn't do it?
Look, you didn't open your eyes,
not even one millimeter.
No way!
Can it be that I am too nervous
to perform?
That's ridiculous!
Maybe the image of yourself moving
and your actual movement aren't in sync.
Let's practice jumping
with your eyes open.
I will train you mercilessly.
So keep up.
Please.
Then...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...
556, 557, 558, 559...
-Jump with your eyes open.
-984, 985...
Three days passed with special training,
day and night.
President, maybe this is enough, right?
You're not as bad at it
as you were before, right?
It's great progress
compared to when you were like a beast.
Not yet.
I can train even more.
Why are you training so hard?
I don't want to show my bad qualities.
If I am to show anything,
it should be my cool side!
Is that meant for the person you like?
That's totally mistaken.
There's nobody special!
You don't have anything to hide, right?
-Who is it?
-Shut up!
Please tell me!
You're too insistent!
We did it! We did it!
Oh, it's thank to you, Secretary Fujiwara.
That was hard!
But you followed through nicely!
All right, Fujiwara.
Next, please teach me
how to throw and receive a ball.
ONE WEEK LATER
-Amazing!
-Shirogane!
Fujiwara?
I raised that kid.
His mother?
Today's result,
Shirogane and Fujiwara win.
WILL YOU TRAIN OTHER ATHLETES AS WELL?
WELL, HONESTLY...
I WILL NEVER DO IT AGAIN.
By the way, the accountant
Ishigami seems to have
finished cleaning up
after the mixer before.
So, there isn't really anything
to do today.
Should we take the day off?
Yes! Then you can call someone
to pick you up, Kaguya.
Actually...
The car that usually picks me up
has a flat tire,
so I will walk home.
What if you are kidnapped?
It's easy to be targeted on rainy days
because it's hard to find any traces.
Please don't make me feel anxious.
I would love to drop you off,
but I have some errands to run today.
-Shinomiya is walking home?
-Thank you for offering.
Then, it might work.
The season's turning point, rainy season.
Sharing an umbrella!
It's the standard event
through which a quick intimacy is achieved
by two people cuddling up
under one umbrella.
The rainy season is the best season
to share an umbrella!
That's stupid.
It's despicable to brush
against one another under one umbrella.
However,
let's acknowledge that the gesture
of sharing an umbrella also makes sense.
When it comes to romance, what you should
fear most is the summer vacation magic.
Summer vacation with a lover.
Within that brand,
an estimation of the opposite sex begins
on school grounds before the vacation.
The sharing of an umbrella with a special
someone has the appeal of intimacy.
It's very effective in excluding someone
as a candidate of a summer romance.
It's raining hard.
It wasn't raining in the morning, but...
Sharing an umbrella
usually occurs in a definite way.
First, person A forgets their umbrella
and is left standing.
Second, person B is unable to remain
indifferent and asks, "Want to share it?"
COMPLETE!
-Then let's go home.
-Therefore,
-in order to share an umbrella,
-Yes.
you have to appeal by forgetting yours.
However...
-Oh, I forgot my umbrella.
Conflict!
Sharing an umbrella begins with the fact
that one person forgets the umbrella.
However, if both forget their umbrellas,
there is no possibility for development.
It just means that they both forgot it.
Did you forget
your umbrella, too, Shinomiya?
Yes.
I usually get picked up,
so it slipped my mind.
What about you?
I forgot to watch the weather report.
I didn't think the weather
would be this bad.
A bluff, of course!
They both have a folding umbrella
in their bags.
What should I do?
Should I tell her I have an umbrella?
But if I do that...
Well, well.
You wanted to share my umbrella so badly
that you lie to me like that?
Good grief.
How cute of you.
It's hopeless!
Pulling out an umbrella now
would expose a meaningful lie.
And that would directly connect to invite
the other person to share an umbrella.
That would be a clear defeat.
Wait a little.
If she didn't have a car,
the staff at the manor
would make her take an umbrella.
There is no way they would be so careless.
I know, President.
You have an umbrella in that bag, right?
You're embarrassed to share it with me,
that's why you're lying like this.
These are the conditions for victory.
There's nothing left,
but to point out that
the other person is lying.
Well, Shinomiya.
You actually have one, right?
Shirogane charged first.
The car had a flat tire on a day it rains.
But today, you who always plans ahead
forgot an umbrella.
I wonder if that's really possible.
What do you want to say?
Nothing in particular.
I lack information.
-I can't get her to admit it after all.
-If anyone is calculated, it's you.
What?
You said earlier
that you missed the weather report,
but that's strange.
What's strange about it?
Even I have days like that.
You always commute by bicycle.
That's right.
Then...
why did you take the train today?
I saw that your bicycle
with a basket up front
wasn't in the parking lot today.
What?
Now that I think about it,
there is nothing strange at all.
When it rains, you commute by train.
It's an understandable behavior.
Right, President?
You said you missed the weather report.
So why did you take
the train today of all days?
You really...
saw it, right?
The weather report.
What a difference being prepared makes.
Were you perhaps
under the impression that I forgot?
President, how about you look again
in that bag of yours?
The difference in preparation
of coming here will decide the outcome.
Shirogane didn't even spend one hour
when planning the sharing of the umbrella.
Kaguya on the other hand,
checked the weather report,
read the weather map thoroughly,
pierced the car's tire with an awl,
checked if the bicycle was there.
Thus, she led by being very prepared.
Of course, she could
foresee this situation, too!
Now, let's double check!
In the end, I have no choice,
but to get drenched walking home.
Kaguya, did you forget your umbrella?
I had an extra umbrella in the classroom,
so please use this!
Please take care from now on!
Don't be so careless, Kaguya.
See you tomorrow!
I was in such a good spot right now!
Just a little longer...
Why is she always getting in the way?
Now, I...
I'll give it to you.
I will give you this umbrella.
Please use it as you like!
But this is Fujiwara's umbrella!
I am subletting it.
But then...
Well...
How about I borrow half of it?
It can't be helped, right?
Today's result,
a tie.
Subtitle translation by Maria Carbune