Got you!
Summer is the season for love.
Hey, cut it out!
Is it because the mischievous sun
turns a young girl's skin golden brown?
Or is it because we're blinded
by the mirage we see on hot asphalt?
Summer open the hearts of boys and girls
and helps them take their relationships
to the next level.
The summer holidays have begun...
And it's already been two weeks!
Nothing exciting
has happened for this guy.
AUGUST 14TH (WED)
I messed up.
I messed up real bad.
23: SHOPPING
24: FIREWORKS
Was that a sigh?
If you sigh like that,
happiness will drift away like the clouds.
Chairman Shirogane says he is at home.
If you wander around here
you are likely to meet him.
Hayasaka, why are you saying
such silly things?
As if I would act like a stalker...
Did you just say he was home?
Hayasaka, since when
have you been in contact
with the Chairman?
It's not what you think.
He sent out a tweet.
Twitter?
What is that?
Wait, I've heard of that.
So Fujiwara is on Twitter?
-Twitter?
-I'm going to take a bath.
RESERVED
Again?
Why is she allowed to do that?
Here we go.
SPLASH
GUSH
Hayasaka come with me right now!
What is it?
The internet is broken!
That's a serious problem.
I tried to use
that thing called Twitter but...
The text is all warped.
That's not a problem.
Should I use the same password
as my bank account?
No.
Internet illiterate.
Kaguya is an analog person.
She relies on mental arithmetic
rather than using a calculator.
Instead of using Google,
she uses a map or encyclopedia.
She only uses the internet
to check the weather and news.
So she only uses the top page
of the search engine.
Her internet skills are at the same level
as the old man who owns the candy store.
Is this okay?
Yes. Ms. Kaguya, you have an account now.
I printed out a list of the accounts
of the Student Council members.
This is the secretary's account.
She spends most of her time tweeting
and not studying at all.
All she does is travel abroad.
This icon is...
Not interested.
Try playing around with it
and get accustomed to using it.
Okay.
I'm going back to taking my bath.
Gosh.
This job is so exhausting.
The only thing that keeps me going
is washing away my stress like this.
Ms. Kaguya doesn't understand.
She should appreciate me more.
Hayasaka! Come quick!
Jeez.
Ms. Kaguya stop barging in...
I've been banned from Twitter!
I'm surprised that you even know
about getting banned.
Look, I can't see anything!
Why? What have I done wrong?
Chairman Shirogane has a private account.
Private account?
There are always trolls
who post hateful comments.
The Chairman has a high level
of internet literacy.
I also keep my main account private.
You should be careful, too.
In other words,
think of your account as your house.
With a normal account,
it's like having your front door wide open
where guests can come and go
as they please.
But people who are cautious
lock their front doors
and give the keys
only to the people that they trust.
Where can you get the key?
That's easy.
Just click on "Follow."
Chairman Shirogane will receive
an approval request.
When you get approved,
you'll be able to read his tweets.
He'll approve if your profile shows
that you're a student at Shuchiin.
I could never...
Do such a thing!
That would be like saying...
Chairman, open the door!
I want to know more about you!
I want to know what you're thinking
and doing every day.
You want to know about me that badly?
The fact that you're obsessed
with my 140-character messages...
How cute.
APPROVAL
That's what approval is, right?
This is a whole new level of stupidity.
You're always thinking of useless things.
Hayasaka, are you mad at me?
I'm not mad but...
I'm wondering how long do you want
to keep me half-naked?
I'm sorry.
If you're not going to do it...
Wait! Hold on!
Hold on!
Let me do it when I'm ready!
FOLLOW
I wonder what the Chairman tweets about?
What does he do? What does he like?
And how is he enjoying his summer?
But...
Right! I'm also making my account private.
When the Chairman follows me...
Please, wake up.
Nobody succeeds that way.
She wasn't able to ask for approval.
Ms. Kaguya is so stubborn
and I can't do anything about it.
They are both helpless.
If they could be more open
about their feelings,
they could easily find happiness.
But I envy them though.
I wish I could love somebody like that.
As if...
Hayasaka! Come quick!
No decision on today's match.
BECAUSE KAGUYA AND SHIROGANE
NEVER SAW EACH OTHER
That's enough!
SHE'S EXTREMELY FAST AT TYPING
CHIKA FUJIWARA IS VERY HUNGRY
Back in Japan!
Egypt was so fun.
I wish I could've stayed a little longer.
The ta'ameya and kushari
were so delicious!
All you're talking about is food.
You might have had fun
but I wanted to come back
to Japan as soon as possible.
Why?
Because...
My name is Saburo Odajima.
I'm an insignificant mid-level manager.
My hobby is going to ramen restaurants.
HAKATA TENRYU RAMEN
Welcome.
I went to a local spot today.
The most popular item
is the tonkotsu ramen...
But that's not what I'm getting.
I'll order the least inconspicous
ramen at the end.
SHOYU TONKOTSU RAMEN
Shoyu tonkotsu with a light broth.
How do you want your noodles?
Firm.
This is the optimal combination here.
It's what a true ramen connoisseur orders.
Welcome.
Wow! It smells so good.
Well, what a cute customer.
Did she mistake this place
for a cake shop?
What would you like?
I would like...
Shoyu tonkotsu with a light broth.
What? Impossible!
How could such a young girl
have known the optimal combination?
Coincidence?
This isn't the kind of place that a girl
would visit alone late at night.
Is this girl...
One of us?
THE CHOSEN ONES
How would you like your noodles?
Well...
Super firm.
Super firm?
She's just following what's trendy.
She's just a young girl after all...
I was unnecessarily worried.
I overestimated her.
Here you go.
Well then...
I'll have to show her
the real way to eat ramen.
First, smell the fragrance of the soup.
The pickled ginger
has the strongest scent,
so you start diagonally from the ginger.
The owner is fully aware of that.
That's why he always place the ginger
the farthest away from the customer.
Next, taste the soup.
Mix in some air while you taste it.
I fully use my sense of smell and taste
to enjoy the flavor.
Next, the noodles.
I take a small amount
and enjoy the texture in my mouth.
Here you go.
Thank you for the meal!
Finally, the chaser.
In order to enjoy the subtle flavors,
you should wash away the oil and salt
from your tongue and reset your palette.
It makes a huge difference
when you do this.
This is one cycle.
We repeat this cycle
which is called mizumawashi.
How is the young girl doing?
Mini ramen!
-She's just a young girl after all.
-Twirl, twirl, twirl.
It looks so delicious.
I can't make fun of her technique.
You can taste all the flavors
at once with the mini ramen.
It is the ultimate form
of "all is one, one is all."
-Eating like that takes time
-Twirl, twirl, twirl.
and the noodles turn soft...
Soft noodles?
Super firm!
-That's why she chose super firm!
-Super firm!
She calculated the time it takes
for the noodles to get soft?
Slurp.
The small toppings are perfect
to make a mini ramen.
It can't be!
If she calculated all of this,
she could be
one of the "four kings."
Mashima Shima from Jimbochyo.
The Hermit from Sugamo.
Or J. Suzuki from Koenji.
THE FOUR KINGS OF TOKYO RAMEN
She has the same level
of skills as that of the top ramen pros!
SAN-CHAN FROM SHIBUYA
Wait a second.
That's right. Not yet.
Sadly,
there is a barrier
that women can't overcome.
That is...
-garlic!
-Garlic!
If you can't stand the smell of garlic,
then you're not a true ramen eater.
-You're a fake.
She ate all of the ingredients.
What will she do?
She can't make mini ramen anymore.
Is she going for it?
Is she going to do it?
CRUNCH
She did it!
She overcame the gender barrier!
I tip my hat to her.
She deserves respect.
She's one of the chosen ones.
She's a true ramen eater!
No way!
She's drinking all the soup?
That's too much salt!
There's garlic in there, too!
But...
-I was young, too.
-It looks so delicious!
-I could do that then, too.
-Thank you for the meal.
Why did I become an old man?
GULP
Go for it!
-The radiant youth that I lost!
-I'm so hungry!
Finish the bowl!
SOUP'S ALL GONE
Thanks for the meal!
Hey...
GOOD JOB
Results of today's ramen match,
Fujiwara is the winner.
WHERE'S YOUR SWITCH
My ramen switch is on!
The summer holidays have begun...
And three weeks have passed.
Nothing exciting
has happened for this guy.
Every day I study, go to work,
eat, take a bath, then sleep.
What a boring summer vacation.
The only promise he made with Kaguya
is to go to the festival
at the end of summer holidays.
Besides that,
they haven't even sent a text
to each other.
Asking each other to go on a date
is an impossible obstacle for them.
It wasn't supposed to be like this.
I wonder what Shinomiya is doing?
Why did this happen?
Ms. Kaguya, that's because...
Your plans are based on the premise
that the Chairman will ask you out.
SUMMER HOLIDAY SCHEDULE
KAGUYA
You're so naive.
Why are you reading you're boss's notebook
without permission?
Why don't you just ask him out?
Don't be ridiculous!
That would give the impression
that I want to go on a date with him!
But that's exactly what you want to do.
Shinomiya...
What are you up to?
DELETE THIS E-MAIL
Am I a girl?
I write an e-mail and then I delete it
again and again!
Is this what first love is like?
Yes, this is first love.
That's it, I quit!
LOOK A LIVE OCTOPUS
CHAIRMAN
IT'S GOING TO GET COLD SO STAY WARM
You're not going to get more e-mails
by reading them over and over.
You even saved that e-mail.
You must have been so happy to get
your first e-mail from the Chairman.
I bet you like it
that he made the first move.
You can't forget him?
Stop it!
That's not what I'm thinking.
Stop analyzing my feelings.
I'm going out.
Hey, brother. Where are you going?
Grocery shopping for dinner.
Wearing your uniform?
I'm going to stop by at school.
But the school is so far away.
What I'm doing is totally pointless.
But I can't just sit around
thinking "What if?"
Nice and cool.
I want to see him.
There's no way she's here.
-I wish the summer holiday
-would be over soon.
NO DECISION FOR TODAY'S MATCH
BECAUSE THEY NEVER SAW EACH OTHER
I have no memories of summer.
Hey, look at me!
But that's not a problem.
I've never been on a family vacation.
It's okay though.
They all treat me like I'm special.
I've never been to a fireworks festival.
It's okay though.
The small fireworks I saw
from my window were pretty enough.
I've never gone shopping with friends.
How about this?
So I feel anxious and excited
at the same time.
It's going to be okay though.
The people that are going with me
are all nice people.
Everything is going to be fine.
I'm used to it.
I never have control over my life.
"My father suddenly asked me
to come back to our main home in Kyoto.
Don't worry about me and have fun."
That's what she said. What should we do?
We're going to...
Postpone!
The whole point is for all of us
to go together.
Good idea. You're right!
I'll call Kei and let her know.
I know, I'm lucky.
I have friends and I was born
into a distinguished family.
I'm blessed with talents
that most people would be envious of.
It's said that the overall balance
of happiness and unhappiness
is the same for everyone.
If that's the case, then it makes sense
that someone, as blessed as me,
have to endure some hardships, too.
Father!
Oh, you're here?
Good.
You came all the way home
and that's all he says?
Drop dead, old man.
My father has never said
"good night" to me.
He's never said "see you later"
or "good job" to me.
I don't remember him
saying "I love you" either.
But it doesn't hurt my feelings.
My life has always been like this.
I don't feel any emotions.
I'll be fine.
People expect me to act like I come
from a dignified family.
They treat me like I'm fragile
and don't want to cause any problems.
They treat me
like a creepy traditional Japanese doll.
But I'll be okay.
Tomorrow, I'm going
to the fireworks festival.
Subtitle translation by Hashim Bharoocha