Schuchiin Academy Campus,
High School Department.
The fourth member of the student council,
the accountant, Yu Ishigami
While this man is indispensable
to the council,
we haven't let you
get a clear picture of him.
The president of the Student Council,
is counting on his ability
so he was chosen to act as an accountant.
This month's accounting report.
-Oh, what is it?
-He is now waiting for an opportunity.
I would like to quit the Student Council.
He was about to quit the Student Council.
I see. You want to quit the council.
Please reconsider!
We will collapse if you leave the council.
I mean it!
Yu Ishigami.
He is an expert in data processing.
In the Shuchiin Academy, there is a system
in which only the president is elected
while all other members are appointed
based on their ability.
Even though
he was only a first year student,
he was already scouted as the president,
for he is an excellent, capable person.
Normally, he works at home,
and is only present at briefing meetings,
but he is a fully-fledged member
of the Student Council.
He is, without a doubt,
the accountant of the Student Council.
-But he was going to quit the council.
-But I have no other choice.
-The reason for that was...
I think I will surely get killed.
Killed?
-By Shinomiya.
-Shinomiya?
I think she will kill me.
What makes you think that?
Her eyes.
Her eyes?
People's eyeballs are an organ
directly connected to the brain.
Usually, half of the brain
is used for the sense of sight.
What people are afraid of,
or what people are starving for,
the brain activity
is shown clearly on the eye movement.
When I see people's eyes,
I understand five or six percent
of their true nature.
Those are strange numbers!
Even I can understand that much.
Shinomiya is sometimes looking at me
with terrible eyes.
She, undoubtedly, wants to kill me.
Just what are you saying happened?
It happened last month.
BRAND COFFEE FOR FREE
Just as I thought, aren't there
many people who find it best to kill time?
What is this?
We can't really go to a coffee shop.
That would get pretty expensive.
That's right.
It would be great
if we had discount coupons for someplace.
NONSENSE
That's right.
Well, as long as it's cheap,
we could go there from time to time.
Don't tell anyone about those tickets.
What was that?
She threatened me,
that's why I can't tell you.
Threatened?
I believe she has already killed
two or three people already.
What happened?
Also, last week...
Shinomiya, do you like the president?
WRONG ANSWER
What did you say? I like the president?
Please, don't say stupid things.
There's no way I would like him.
Don't you think he's boyfriend material?
What? Of course not...
Really?
I'm really bothered
by being the subject of such rumors!
Is that so?
I thought you looked good together.
Then, I will go to the president
and tell all of that in your place.
I'll say that it's hopeless.
Don't you dare tell him that.
Do you understand that?
I think she can go so far
as having me assassinated.
Assassinated?
Using the sofa corner
to attack and strangle me
was a professional move.
Just who do you think Shinomiya is?
I think she likely has
the nature of a serial killer.
You can see it in her eyes.
Isn't he too confident
considering his lack of accuracy?
Fujiwara is in even more danger than I am.
She sometimes looks at her
as if she wasn't even human.
I think she's got
less than two months to live.
You've already done the calculations?
Don't be stupid!
No, people like her
are the most dangerous.
President?
Have you seen Ishigami?
The conference earlier...
Don't make it worse for yourself!
It's regarding the budget
of the drama club.
Surrender yourself, Shinomiya!
Hey!
Listen to me first!
Didn't I tell you that the drama club
needs some assistance?
They are fitting the costume today.
Yes.
Even so, you didn't need
to bring that prop with you.
Well...
That is because
I was in the mood for a little prank.
I am sorry.
She's cute.
Shirogane, this is a trap.
She is acting cute,
so you'll let your guards down
then she'll cut you up.
Don't say scary things.
That is just a costume,
Shinomiya wouldn't kill anyone!
President!
Please, help me.
Kaguya killed me off!
As I thought!
Just what are you thinking?
It's just a special makeup.
Oh, that's right.
No, President.
This is also a trap.
Maybe she really died,
and Shinomiya performed
a creepy operation on her.
Accountant Ishigami.
You always think too much.
Shinomiya would never kill anybody.
Try to believe more in your friends, okay?
Believe in friends?
That's amazing, by the way.
Right?
How did you apply it?
Just like this!
I am sorry.
Believe in friends.
Ishigami?
About that matter...
I am happy
you didn't talk to anyone about it.
It's a virtue
to be able to keep your mouth shut.
Next time, if you talk...
Believe?
I wouldn't be using this toy knife, okay?
Also, please stop bothering the president.
Don't talk about quitting
the council anymore, okay?
-Will you also stab the president?
-What if she...
-Is it okay? I want to try it, too!
-by any chance...
was listening from the start?
Today's result...
ISHIGAMI WANTED TO QUIT BUT HE CAN'T
BECAUSE HE WAS SCARED OF KAGUYA
...Ishigami lost.
THE WOMAN OF LOVE AND HATE
You are seeing different animal cages.
How many cats can fit into that one?
Why are you asking me
such an abstract question?
It's a psychological test.
I borrowed this from the library.
Just by answering these questions,
I can get a clear and comprehensive image
of your deep psyche.
That's worthless.
You think you can understand people
just by asking these questions?
Well, let's just try it anyway.
How many cats?
I think about nine cats?
This is the number of kids
you want to have.
Amazing! It's on point!
-Nine! That's a large family!
-Nine! That many?
Psychological test.
A test that draws out a person's
true nature with abstract questions.
Many elements of the game have cited
a strong influence of the Barnum effect.
But among those, there are also practical
results based on psychology.
This test has brought painful experiences
when people thought about it
entirely as a game and were negligent.
There are many
other interesting questions.
Let's play it together.
Do you want us to join, too?
Yes.
Ready, everyone?
You are walking on a gloomy road.
And somebody taps your shoulder
from behind.
Who do you think it is?
Give me another hint.
It's not a quiz so
it doesn't work like that.
I see.
A gloomy road.
Just what is that suggesting?
I know it!
It's the second question on page 47!
The answer to that is...
it is the person that you like!
If you said the name
of the person you like,
it's would turn out like a confession.
As usual, she was prepared
for this situation as well.
She was friends with Chika Fujiwara
since childhood.
Kaguya knows her behavioral patterns well.
Ever since she saw the book
has been added to the library,
she guessed that it was very likely
for Fujiwara to bring it to the council.
Kaguya thoroughly checked that book.
Question!
You found a squirrel.
-She could avoid dangerous answers.
-What do you do with it?
Let me see.
I would cook for her every day
and massage her before she goes to sleep.
The answer is...
that is how would you treat your partner
after marrying him.
In other words,
when it comes to the minefield
of this psychological test,
she had a great advantage.
That's right. My answer is you, Fujiwara.
What? Me?
A gloomy road...
Why are you running away, Ishigami?
For me... it was Shinomiya.
Me?
Is that how he feels?
He's a good kid
and it's not like I hate him, but...
I am sorry.
I can only think of him
about as much as I do of a cricket.
Ishigami was rejected.
Well, the problem is the president.
Kaguya is cold and scared,
she doesn't like this.
President, let's go back together.
That's true. I am...
Now.
Wait!
Why is she smiling like that?
She said it's an interesting question.
What that romantic brain of hers
is interested in
can't be a proper test.
What if the answer to that is
the person you like?
Well, President.
Deep down you always liked
me very much, right?
How cute of you!
That would be like confessing my feelings!
I have to pick someone with whom
I have a relationship they approve of.
Then...
That would be my sister, probably.
The person who tapped your shoulder
is the one you like.
In other words,
you have a sister complex, President.
You're the most boring among us.
Yes, I have a complex.
I like Shinomiya?
Why does it feel terrible?
President, I am suffering from
the Stockholm Syndrome so I am going home.
Take care.
It probably coincides
with misattribution of arousal.
I am going to the hospital.
I want to answer questions, too,
so let's search some on the internet.
Damn it!
Fujiwara will pick some questions
outside of the book!
Oh, this is cute!
You are now on a broad field of flowers.
The person who owns it told you
to pick as many flowers you as like.
How many do you pick?
It's a question of which you don't know
what the answer symbolizes.
Flowers?
I would pick beautiful flowers
and cherish them.
I wouldn't need a lot of them.
I would pick enough
to make a flower bouquet
that I would love.
I see.
What should I do?
I answered without noticing.
How many would you pick, President?
Well, it's the same system as before.
So maybe I should answer it normally.
You can pick flowers you like for free?
Then my answer can
only definitely be this one.
I would fill a truck with flowers
and drive it away.
I think the truck
wouldn't be enough either.
You have a poor person's mentality.
What would you do with so many flowers?
-It would be easy to give or sell them.
-The answer is...
THE QUANTITY OF FLOWERS YOU PICKED
SHOWS HOW MUCH YOU LOVE SOMEBODY
What was the answer?
It was how much you love flowers.
That was about it.
-But I love flowers!
-That's stupid.
I don't agree with this.
That's true.
-Today's result,
-But that's what it says.
-Shirogane lost.
-So you have to accept it.
COST OF A FAMILY
IF YOU GET THE HCG VACCINE
THERE IS A 20% CHANCE YOU WILL HAVE TWINS
Should we get a smoothie on the way home?
Okay!
I want a celery one.
What should we do?
I am sorry!
I need to work part-time today.
I have to go straight there?
Again?
You work too much.
You're definitely coming next time!
Sure!
It's time to go home, Ms. Kaguya.
Hayasaka.
I told you not to come
to the Student Council room.
I checked first if the president
and the others have gone home.
Please, relax.
This kind of negligence is fatal.
You haven't been paying attention lately.
Those clothes,
the nails and your skirt's length
are all violating the school regulations.
They're all within school regulations.
Well, there are several loopholes
in the school regulation.
Several?
For us, beauty is power.
BEAUTY IS POWER
People who don't beautify themselves
don't belong in high society.
I don't want my chance to be stolen
by a woman who is only pretty.
And you are too formal, Ms. Kaguya.
Even in this high school,
nail polish has gotten popular lately.
If you want boys to think you are cute,
you should develop
a taste for such things.
Really?
If I did that, the president...
No,
the boys would think I am cute?
You have been wearing
such tattered clothes so far.
Of course.
Hayasaka realized that nail polish
didn't much matter with the opposite sex.
However...
For boys...
Anyway, let's get back quickly
and paint those nails.
-The desire to dress Kaguya stylishly...
-How do you mean?
-Influenced her answer.
-What is it?
NEXT DAY
They used a kind of nail polish
that wouldn't violate the dress code.
The limestone painted on the ring finger
has an appeal to modesty.
What will the president think?
Will he think it's cute?
Or... maybe he will think
I'm being shallow?
What are you intending to do?
What's with those nails?
They're just nice.
I would hate it if he asked me like that.
I'll go home today, after all.
What are you doing, Shinomiya?
Aren't you going in?
No, I am going in.
Kaguya!
I have a question about this part.
Yes, what is it?
Are you hiding something behind your back?
No, nothing at all.
She always has good intuition
in times like this.
If someone were to notice,
I want it to be the president.
Even if it's wrong,
I don't want this kid to notice.
I have to get closer to him.
President, this is a record
of the proceedings of the other day.
Thank you.
This part here is the problem.
That's right.
It's a big problem.
You are right!
He didn't notice!
Shinomiya is getting fashionable!
Why didn't he notice?
Does this mean he is not interested in me?
Why did she change her attitude?
She always says,
"Does a swan need to dress up?"
She never paid attention to fashion.
What should I do?
Is this something I can allude to?
You have a body fit for bearing children.
Wouldn't that be considered
a matter of sexual harassment?
Also, lately...
Kei, isn't that skirt too short?
It's not like
I was showing it to you, bro.
And that's sexual harassment, by the way.
I was just worried about her as a brother.
Anyone's reaction,
except for the person that you want,
has a tendency
to be considered as sexual harassment.
However, I should at least
let her know that I noticed.
She probably won't insult me
worse than my sister did.
Fujiwara.
You changed your conditioner, right?
You noticed that?
Oh, well.
The smell is different than usual.
Today, you could say that it's stuffy,
but it smells adorable than usual.
If I were to compare
it to your smell before,
it's like a baby's smell.
Ishigami.
That's creepy.
I want to die...
I want to die, so I will go home.
Okay, but don't die.
I wanted to compliment her,
because it smelled nice.
Do I smell? Is it bad?
That was harsh!
The day Shinomiya tells me I am creepy,
I will also want to die!
I think, it's best
not to mention the nails.
The risk is too high.
I don't want to look creepy.
No. Is this also an excuse?
This is my problem.
Complimenting her nails is...
I simply...
I feel embarrassed.
In the end, he didn't notice my nails.
But I think it's better
that he didn't notice.
As I thought,
there's no point in dressing up stylishly.
I won't become cute.
Shinomiya!
Those nails!
They're...
No, nothing at all.
What was it?
Tell me, please!
He wanted to say that you are cute.
She also thinks he's cute.
What was he trying to say?
What do you think, Hayasaka? Hayasaka!
-Did he notice them?
-Today's result, Kaguya won.
Subtitle translation by Maria Carbune