The thunder gods
will steal my belly button!
Are you that scared of lightning?
Because it is so sudden.
And then it goes, "boom!"
I hate loud sounds!
Then why don't you cover your ears?
If I use my hands for that,
they will steal my belly button!
It's logical if you think about it!
What's logical about it?
Local trains.
I will hide my belly button,
so please cover my ears, Kaguya.
Okay.
TRAIN SERVICES ARE CANCELLED
The trains are canceled
because of the typhoon!
That's not good.
You should call home.
My family doesn't have a car,
so they can't help me.
What will I do?
I see.
I should offer to drive him home.
President, if you'd like...
Oh, that would be like... a driving date!
Driving date.
That is certainly also a kind of date.
Shoulders touching in a tight space,
listening to the pleasant FM radio,
driving through the city
while talking about this and that.
And then at a red light...
It would be so nice
if the light didn't turn green
and we could stay like this.
That's what she would think.
Strictly speaking, they wouldn't be alone
because Kaguya's driver is there,
but for Kaguya this would be a drive date.
In short...
It hurts, that hurts!
Then I would be inviting him on a date!
-What's wrong, Shinomiya?
-Nothing.
Nothing at all.
It would be better
if it came from the president.
There's no way I can invite him like that.
But to let him find his way home
when he has no means of transportation...
That's right!
There would be no problem
if he would ask me to drop him off!
It seems that my taxi is coming soon.
I see.
I'm screwed...
Eh?
Doesn't he have a way to go home?
It seems so.
Then let me drop...
A lightning stroke outside!
I will cover your ears
so you can't hear anything.
Thank you.
While I'm at it,
I will cover your eyes as well.
Why do you have to do that?
Well, then.
-I'll bring you to the taxi like this.
-Wait a minute, Kaguya!
It's scary!
But also, a little fun!
What game are they playing?
Well, now that the most troublesome kid
has gone home,
I won't be bothered.
But how do I get him
to ask me to drop him off?
This is bad,
I still have to go to my part-time job.
I will lose a shift if this continues.
That's right.
To miss a shift because of a typhoon
would disqualify you as a working adult.
You could either call a taxi
that costs as much as you earn per day,
or you could ask somebody to drop you off.
It's an obvious choice
for any true grown-up, right?
This was efficient.
I will think about it
on the way to the toilet.
Please do so.
Is hard to imagine
that the cheapskate president
would call a cab.
Then, naturally, he would come
bowing to me as clear as day.
I won this round!
Forty-five dollars.
With a salary of nine dollars per hour,
that means five hours of work.
But I don't want to miss my shift!
Oh, no!
The trains are running again!
What's up with this timing?
Try a little harder, typhoon!
There's nothing else left to do but that.
The Seven Anti-Shirogane Measures,
number one.
The rechargeable battery is dead.
Kaguya always plans
for every possible situation.
She has prepared traps
to trick Shirogane with.
This rechargeable battery is one of them!
I have about a minute until
the president comes back from the toilet.
I have to change his battery in that time.
The time is very short
and the degree of difficulty is very high,
but I can do it!
What's wrong, Shinomiya?
Nothing, I'm doing a light exercise.
My battery died?
Hey, can I use your phone?
My car has also come to pick me up.
Excuse me.
See you tomorrow.
If I just wait here...
Shinomiya, are you going back by car?
Please!
Can you give me a lift, please?
Since you're asking so passionately,
I cannot refuse you.
I will bring the miserable president home.
Are you a god?
Ms. Kaguya.
That's quite a cute plan,
but how will I be able to go home?
By walking?
Are you a devil?
If you don't cherish me more,
you will get your punishment.
You with your punishments...
I told you.
I was kidding.
Of course,
I called a taxi for you, Hayasaka.
Damn it!
I also...
saw this coming.
Then you should have stopped me sooner.
I will skip school today, too.
I'll be back.
I'll just make you a porridge.
No!
Stay with me, Hayasaka!
It's too bad.
You're not usually this cute.
Shinomiya caught a cold?
Continuing to the nerve-racking incident
of the home visit.
It's good! This phone
can do a lot of things. It's great!
SHIROGANE'S SECOND-HAND
SMARTPHONE
WITH NO INSURANCE GOT A NEW BATTERY.
It seems that Shinomiya has caught a cold.
That means we have to bring her
the handouts.
I will go!
Secretary Fujiwara?
I only visited her when she was sick once.
When Kaguya is sick,
she totally acts like a pampered child!
Pampered?
President, can you please wipe my back?
She's really cute!
You know? You can hug her as much
as you want and she won't get mad.
President, hug me tightly!
But visiting her alone would be unfair.
Let's all go together.
All of us?
Yes.
Visiting a sick person in a large group
would be senseless.
I think it's enough if one person goes.
I'm scared so I don't want to go.
Well, that's true.
Who should go, then?
Let's decide by playing a memory game.
Memory game.
As everyone knows, it's a common game.
We won't use jokers.
And if someone is caught cheating,
he will lose five points, okay?
Let's decide who starts
with rock-paper-scissors.
President, start the game!
Let's start!
I caught you, Secretary Fujiwara!
What is it, President?
Well, there are several
frustrating things.
First is that you would challenge us
to a memory game.
That is a little strange
for this occasion.
Usually, you would pick a game
you are more skilled at.
Then you mentioned so nonchalantly
that anyone who cheats
should lose five points
instead of being instantly disqualified.
That made me cautious.
If you hadn't said anything,
I probably would have missed it.
What are these signs
that look like numbers?
These are playing cards for cheating!
Is that true?
Fujiwara, you're an underhanded
cheap shot!
Then you got caught
by the tactic you used to cheat!
You're so shameful!
That's so embarrassing!
If it were me, I would go home.
-Shame!
-That's enough, Ishigami.
We agreed on how to punish someone
who cheats
and this is behavior
is also within the rule.
It's fair because we only touched them.
That's right!
If I haven't been caught in the act,
then it's not cheating!
No, you were caught.
Starting over.
In the first half of the game,
these corrupt but still talented players
correctly identified
the position of each card.
Making no mistakes,
they gathered all the points properly.
Shirogane earned ten points,
Fujiwara eight points,
and Ishigami earned ten points.
There are now 24 cards remaining.
With this, I am in a tie with Ishigami.
President, wipe the front, too. Please!
As expected,
you all have a good memory.
So I'll make it a little harder for you!
What?
Changing the location!
Moving the cards
they desperately tried to remember
is particularly a dirty strategy.
POSITION CHANGE
This is bad!
I don't know where they are anymore.
By changing the position of the cards,
Fujiwara earned significantly more points.
Finally, she got back the points
she lost by cheating.
Now, enjoy the game, everybody!
Oh, no. I'm last.
If this carries on, I won't get to
see Shinomiya being a pampered baby.
President, can you caress me?
What gift should I bring her?
I rarely have a chance
to give her something!
She got too drenched last night,
it's no wonder she caught a cold.
Drenched? Shinomiya?
But she was driven home.
Well, I just happened to see her.
She was waiting for somebody
outside the school gate.
Could she have been waiting for me?
I don't have any proof...
If that's true,
I shouldn't be thinking
about pampered Shinomiya.
I am idiot who thinks only
about stupid things.
In this case, it really should be me
who's going to visit her.
Don't think about stupid things!
Concentrate!
Thirteen.
Thirteen!
Damn it! If she wins,
she'll get to have this, too!
It was false.
Is this just a normal mistake?
No way!
I see!
It's your turn, President!
Take this!
And this!
I win.
Conclusion, first place goes to Shirogane.
That was some fierce catch-up!
Oh well, this is what happens
when you understand the trick.
The trick?
These cards are special
because the patterns on them
aren't symmetrical.
That's why you can use them like this.
That's right!
They look like numbers on a watch.
Yes.
If you place them at the right angle,
they can show the numbers one to twelve.
And the card number thirteen
was problematic,
so Fujiwara put it farthest away.
The position change
was also meant to hide this trick.
Fujiwara.
You're a cheater!
Underhanded! A cheater!
You don't learn at all!
You should be ashamed!
Where do you get such shamelessness?
And then he beat you
by discovering how you cheated?
That's the most embarrassing!
So shameful.
That is so shameful, Fujiwara!
Don't look at me!
I just...
I just wanted to visit Shinomiya!
I want to die, so I'm going home.
Is that so?
But please don't die!
And yet I somehow managed
to trick my sisters through that.
She really is a cheater!
Is that why they say that analog gamers
are superficial?
It's like she fell into her own trap.
This happens when you do something
that doesn't suit you.
I wonder if this is how Shinomiya learned.
If it were Shinomiya...
Oh, crap. I'm getting a little nervous.
What should I give her?
I want to eat canned peaches, Hayasaka.
Sure.
The sickbed visit continues in part two.
TODAY'S RESULT,
BOTH OF THEM LOST
BECAUSE NEITHER OF THEM HAD A STRATEGY.
Is this the famous Shinomiya villa?
I saw it on the internet,
but it's even more amazing in real life.
I probably should have brought
more than drinks and jelly.
I am responsible
for the care of Ms. Kaguya.
My name is Smithee A. Hayasaka.
I am pleased to make your acquaintance.
COLORED CONTACTS
A LITTLE PADDED
It's a maid!
I see you have come to visit
Ms. Kaguya on her sickbed.
Oh, yes. That's right.
Then I will show you to her room, sir.
Oh, no. About that...
I only came to deliver
these handouts to Shinomiya.
If you could please
give these to her, Ms. Hayasaka.
Don't get spooked after you made it here.
There, there.
But, you know...
No, no.
I think it's best
if you give them directly to Ms. Kaguya.
But!
Ms. Kaguya,
you have a visitor.
Hey! What are you doing, Ms. Kaguya?
DIRTY!
I can't find it.
What are you looking for?
Fireworks.
Fireworks?
Let's light some fireworks
together, Hayasaka!
No, we won't.
I understand you get ahead of yourself
because summer vacation is coming soon,
but treating your cold is our priority.
You're a meanie! I want fireworks!
Never mind that,
there is a guest here for you.
A guest?
It's the president!
Why are you here?
Oh, well...
Are you living here now?
Why am I not aware of that?
No, I am not. I'm not living here!
Ms. Hayasaka, what's this?
According to Sigmund Freud,
human behavior
is determined by desire and reason.
The human instinct constantly
creates the id,
and the ego has the role
of controlling those desires.
However,
if one loses the ability to think
that is at the base
of the ego for some reason,
one becomes a beast controlled by our id.
In other words, you become an idiot.
An idiot?
People who usually use their brain
as much as possible
are most affected at times like these.
At first glance,
it seems like she's awake,
but she is like a person in a dream.
When she gets well,
all of her memories during the time
that she was sick will be gone.
It's the same as being drunk.
There she goes,
saying strange things again.
Well, I have to get back to work soon.
I'll leave Ms. Kaguya in your care.
I understand.
Is it all right?
Nobody will come into this room
for about three hours.
Under no circumstances
should you do anything strange.
I won't.
Additionally, this room
is completely soundproofed.
Ms. Kaguya won't remember anything,
if you did anything
you wouldn't get caught.
But you should absolutely
not do anything weird.
I'm telling you I won't!
I bought several drinks for you.
Do you want one?
Fireworks?
No, not fireworks.
It's no use.
I can't talk to her
about anything serious right now.
Honestly speaking,
I was hoping I could help her drink
or do other wicked things,
but she really is weak.
If I took advantage of this,
I could find out what she really feels
or what her weakness is, but...
Shinomiya.
Did you by any chance
get sick because of me?
Yesterday, you wanted
to give me a ride, right?
And that's why
you were waiting at the school gate.
I don't know.
It feels like it's true
but it also feels like it's not.
Which is?
Are you mad at me, President?
I am sorry.
No, you didn't do anything.
No.
I always cause you trouble.
You know, I never know what I should do.
It's my first time
being in this kind of situation,
so I really don't know what to do.
That's why I only do it
the only way I know how.
I don't know any other way to do it.
I can only do it like this.
That's why today...
let's sleep together.
What? No, Shinomiya!
Are you being shy?
How cute of you.
Wait a little!
Shinomiya won't remember any of this
and nobody will come in this room.
This situation is too convenient!
I am not sure I can control myself!
Just what have I
gotten myself into?
ID
EGO
SLEEP-DEPRIVED
What time is it?
It feels like I've been sleeping
for a long time.
President!
Why are you in my bed?
I just came over...
What kind of man who slips
into a woman's bed without permission?
But you invited me!
There's no way I'd do that!
How dare you get in while I was sleeping!
You're the worst!
Get out of here!
Oh, my.
I thought it would turn out like this.
Well, it seems you had a good sleep.
Hayasaka!
How far did I go with him?
It's not for me to tell.
How irritating!
It's so annoying that I can't stand it.
I tried so hard to hold it back!
The nerve-racking home visit incident
comes to a close.
Well, maybe you didn't do it.
Subtitle translation by Maria Carbune