CONFESSION
-When you fall in love with someone...
-Will you...
go out with me?
You confess your love...
and it'll be accepted.
Anyone would tell you
that it's a wonderful thing,
but everything about that is wrong!
Even between lovers,
there is always a clear power struggle.
There is the one who exploits
and the one who is being exploited.
One who crushes and one who gets crushed.
There's always a winner and a loser.
You're saying
you want to live an honorable life,
then you should,
by no means, not become the loser.
Love is a war!
The moment you fall in love, you lose.
The private Shuchiin Academy.
This prestigious school,
with its ancient and noble origin,
was founded to educate the pupils
born in the upper crust of the society.
Even though the nobility class system
has been abolished,
students from distinguished families,
-who will, one day, rule the country...
-How do you do?
-...continues to attend this academy.
Of course, they wouldn't let
just ordinary people to lead
-and bring these students together.
-Everyone!
Look.
The members of the Student Council!
Kaguya Shinomiya,
the vice president of the Student Council.
Total assets, two hundred trillion yen.
Being the eldest daughter
of the Shinomiya Group,
who owns more than a 1,000 subsidiaries,
and four industrial groups,
she is definitely a genuine young woman.
Just like the superiority
of her bloodline,
she is, undoubtedly,
a talented young woman.
With such brilliant talents
in arts, music, and martial arts.
She is Kaguya Shinomiya.
Meanwhile,
the man supporting Shinomiya is...
Miyuki Shirogane,
the president of the Student Council.
Sincere, vigorous,
sensible, and intelligent,
he always ranks number one
in the mock examinations.
In contrast to the talented Kaguya,
he earns respect and awe
as an experienced scholar.
Due to his exemplary conduct,
even if he just transferred to the school,
he was selected to be the president
of the Student Council.
He, then, gets to wear
the pure gold braided cord
that has been passed down
through generations for 200 years.
They look so good together
every time I see them!
It's like watching the gods
roaming around.
I wonder if they are dating?
Will you ask them about it, please?
No way!
It would be rude to just approach them.
I could never...
It seems like...
people are gossiping about us.
They're wondering
if we are a couple or not.
They're probably at that age of curiosity.
It's best to ignore them.
Is that so?
The thought of me dating Shinomiya...
These people sure are having fun
talking trash about love affairs.
How stupid.
But then...
if Shinomiya really wants to date me,
then I would think about it.
She is interested in me, that's for sure.
So, is it only a matter of time?
I will quickly tear down her mask
of being a perfect little woman.
-She will come to me blushing and begging.
-President, I long for you.
These ordinary, ignorant people
are at it again.
Just who do they think I am?
I am someone from the Shinomiya family,
the heart of the country.
How could they think
that I'm dating such an ordinary person?
Well, it is true
that I have a duty to fulfill
because he is the president
of the Student Council.
But if he would kneel
and offer me his heart, and even his home,
I could train him to be a man
who's worthy of me.
Besides, is there a man who can resist
falling deeply in love with me?
It's only a matter of time.
While they were both
under their thoughts...
half a year has already gone by!
During that period of time,
nothing out of the ordinary happened.
STUDENT COUNCIL PRESIDENT
By the way,
the apple tree by the fountain
and the cherry fruits relief
are full of snails.
My little sister once went into a fountain
because it was hot and she got a cold.
Nothing good really comes out
when you start acting on your emotions.
In this uneventful time,
their thoughts went from
"It would be nice to date"
to "how can I make the other
confess to me?"
Meanwhile, on the other side of the table,
someone was completely unaware
of this sophisticated strategy.
STUDENT COUNCIL SECRETARY
Oh, by the way.
FUJIWARA CHIKA
Please listen.
I surprisingly won two tickets
to the cinema,
but I'm forbidden from watching
these kinds of films at home.
LOVE REFRAIN
So do you two want to see it instead?
Now that you mention it,
surprisingly, I'm actually free
on the weekend.
-If that's so, Shinomiya...
-You know, there's this rumor going on.
That if you see this movie with somebody,
you two will become a couple.
How lovely!
Then, President,
did you just invite me?
You want to take me to the cinema
and watch a movie
that makes people become a couple?
My, my.
That's completely...
That would be like confessing to her!
Shirogane, that's a sudden dilemma!
The rule of a romantic relationship is,
"The one who falls in love, loses!"
And because they are both
filled with pride,
neither of them can freely express
their love for each other.
What should I do?
Honestly speaking,
I'll just have to deceive her.
Will you sell them with me
at the ticket shop?
Oh, my.
You, out of all people,
are panicking and making a fuss out of it?
How cute of you.
I won't let that happen!
I, Shirogane,
shouldn't be the one to back down!
The one who would run away
should be you, Shinomiya.
Oh, yes. I did invite you to the cinema.
I don't really believe
those kinds of groundless rumors,
but you seem to like the idea of it.
Do you want to see this movie with me?
That moment, Shinomiya thought...
After showing so much interest
on how you want to see the movie with me,
you're suddenly
leaving the decision up to me?
That's a nice turn of events.
Even if I have the choice
of refusing his invitation,
all of the work I've done
would become useless.
YOU HAVE WON
Purposely fabricating the prize Chika won,
and putting it personally on her mailbox.
Oh, yes!
The plan of choosing a day
I knew he would be free on...
will all be useless!
Then if I refuse his invitation now,
there might not be another chance
for him to invite me
to something like this.
For a young lady, it's a no!
I am not saying yes
to this kind of choice!
I... see...
In the end, I still can't help myself
but to believe in those kinds of stories,
so if I were to go with you,
I would like you to, at least, ask me
with a little more enthusiasm.
She's using her
"Play the innocent girl" skills!
It's a negotiation skill
that runs in the Shinomiya family.
This calculated facial expression
is said to make
even the hearts of gods beat faster.
In fact, Shirogane's thoughts
are now also dispersed.
Well, confessing
is most likely a man's job.
While Shirogane
was clouded with his thoughts,
there's no way Shinomiya will let
this chance slip through her hands.
She enacted her plan in an instant.
I think I am at the age when I would like
to experience love, even just once.
The battle of wits presents itself
like a chess problem.
Shinomiya is the one who is pursuing,
while Shirogane is looking
for a chance to reverse the game.
The intelligence of these geniuses
who can see two or three moves ahead
surpasses that of ordinary people
in its speed as they crash.
Kaguya is strengthening her defense.
Shirogane is about to crumble.
Their thoughts are heading towards
forming a logical conclusion.
The person who completes the conclusion
will be the victor...
If you hate romantic movies,
I also have tickets
for Saving the Tottori Bird!
Saving...
The Tottori Bird?
Chaos Theory.
Due to the sudden remarks
of Fujiwara, the secretary,
the theory got jumbled up
just before it was completed
by a little bit of chaos that entered it.
This mere sparkle of chaos
can result in an explosion
as big as the Big Bang.
To deal with the increasing number
of choices,
-the two geniuses have to force...
-What's wrong?
their brains to go beyond its limits.
And the result,
their brains suddenly want
large quantities of sugar!
The only existing source of sugar
in this room is the steamed bun.
So that means,
the one who gets the steamed bun
is the victor!
The afternoon classes
are about to start, right?
See you after school, then!
This is the sophisticated war of love
fought by the two geniuses
who are filled with pride and ingenuity.
TODAY'S BATTLE RESULTS
BOTH OF THEM LOST
Let me repeat!
This is a sophisticated war of love
fought by the two geniuses
who are filled with pride and ingenuity.
A love letter?
Yes, the content is very passionate,
he is asking me
to eat at the cafeteria just once.
In other words, he's asking you out?
A love letter for Shinomiya?
It seems like there are also stupid men
when it comes to love.
We are referring to the Shinomiya
who spends her time staring at me.
Does this guy know that compared to me,
everyone else just looks like
a talking weed
-or he just haven't noticed it yet?
-Hello!
There's no way she'd go out with him.
Do you plan to go out with him?
Of course.
Have you lost your mind, Shinomiya?
How can you accept
a stranger's invitation so recklessly?
This person can muster up the courage
to write such a passionate
love letter to me.
I'm sure I will fall in love with him.
You idiot!
Like I would just stand by and watch.
I have to stop Shinomiya
in any way possible.
Don't go on a date with another man!
Does it bother you so much
that another man got to be with me?
How cute of you.
That would be the same as confessing!
I can't say something
that would sound like I like her!
That is something...
-I want to avoid happening at all costs!
-Kaguya, are you really going to go?
Yes. I'm already looking forward to it.
This behavior of Kaguya seems like that
of an unprincipled girl in love.
There is no way I would go.
What could this kid be thinking?
A bluff, of course!
If I were to be invited by someone,
someone would have to offer me a country,
and then I would decide if they're worthy.
Who would like to do charity work?
How rude of me
-to expect her to date a weed!
-Weed, weed!
After all, this is a strategy
to make Shirogane stop her.
A battle of love and wits!
Between two haughty people,
where none of them
can confess their love on their own.
So there is no choice
but to use their talents and ingenuity
and make the opposing side confess.
Is there a way to stop her
as casual as possible? Think!
His intelligence is tested!
It's no use.
As long as he doesn't bow his head
and ask me obediently, I won't back down.
What a clever tactic.
This is indeed the battle
of love and wits!
The duel unfolds between the two.
Shinomiya,
as the President of the Student Council,
I can't recommend
an illicit sexual affair.
He found another approach.
Speaking not as a normal individual,
but as the Student Council President.
That's a very clever perspective.
Don't exaggerate.
I'm just going to the cafeteria.
The teachers would judge you.
It's entirely possible
to be suspended from school over this.
If you really want to go, so be it.
I will tell the teachers on your behalf.
A snitch to teachers!
While it can be very effective,
it's a risky choice that labels the person
who used it as a coward forever,
but for Shirogane, stopping Shinomiya
is more important than his honor.
This resoluteness also worked on Kaguya.
I didn't think he would really use
such a forbidden move,
but I must go forward with it.
I don't mind.
If it were true love, I would even
accept expulsion from the school.
Expulsion?
For true love, I am prepared
to offer my whole body and soul.
Her whole body and soul?
-Big damage to Shirogane!
-Stupid!
What a stupid thing to say!
It's not stupid!
He has declared
his passionate love for me.
I would be ungrateful
if I didn't answer it
by being prepared to risk expulsion!
This is not something to joke about!
And what if I was the one
who confessed to you?
Hypothetically speaking.
Hypothetically.
Could you forget about that man?
There...
There is a possibility.
Is that what you call true love, then?
If you could forget about him
just because another man confessed to you,
then it can't be true love.
I only said that there was a possibility.
I see, I see. What a tremendous love.
If he were really worried about me,
he should stop me
without caring about how he looks like!
I don't know anymore,
but I am really going.
If he doesn't confess passionately
enough to make me cry,
I will really go!
President...
I don't want you
to belong to someone else, Kaguya!
-I don't want you to be expelled!
-Fujiwara...
No, no, I don't want to lose you!
Jeez!
I won't go, so let go of me!
Today's result, Kaguya lost.
A PASSIONATE LOVE LETTER HAS ARRIVED
BY HAYASAKA
You can't!
Why? It's okay, just let me have one bite!
All right, but...
There you go! Open up!
That's improper!
Are you really that furious about it?
They're not aware of their status
as students of the traditional Shuchiin.
To coax things out of each other
in public like that.
It's despicable!
It's vulgar and ridiculous.
That's an awful way of describing it.
President, do you have
a home-made lunch today?
My grandpa from the countryside
sent me a lot of vegetables.
-I know it's tasty despite how it looks.
-Miyuki, eat properly!
For Kaguya, that lunch was the first
magnificent sight in her life.
Kaguya's lunch was prepared
by a team of chefs
and delivered to her.
It was a lunch menu
based on a perfect nutritional balance
and an assortment of seasonal ingredients.
That was the lunch box Kaguya knew.
Fried food, red wiener sausage,
rolled omelet,
hamburgers, pickled plumbs, and...
rice seasoning.
All the things she wanted to eat
stuffed together inside a lunchbox
just like in a child's treasure,
her heart longed fiercely
for such freedom.
Octopus-shaped sausages.
They really exist!
I want to try them, but...
-Kaguya's pride wouldn't allow for it.
-Lunch, lunch!
Are you having a lunch box today?
It looks delicious!
Is that so? I made everything myself.
Oh, can I have a bite?
I don't really mind.
Really?
Yes, so do you want this hamburger?
-All right!
-Fujiwara?
I WANT IT
This is delicious!
Hamburgers are tasty when it's still hot
with all the juices flowing inside it,
but they're even better
at normal temperature!
I ate everything already
while all the flavors are still inside!
Okay, then eat this one, too!
Yes!
Fujiwara.
I thought you were my friend,
but if you were to die tomorrow,
I wouldn't help you.
What's with that disdainful look
on Shinomiya's face?
Is she really...
Is she really despising my lunch box
that much?
How dare she laugh at me!
I'll teach her a lesson!
That's hot miso soup!
The rice grows cold and hard,
but if you eat it with the miso soup,
in that moment,
it suddenly becomes the best thing.
Try it out.
Okay.
Wait, why is she eating
from parts where Shirogane has eaten?
That's like an indirect kiss!
From the cup, too?
The rice...
the rice is melting in my mouth!
That's right. From old times,
cold rice had an established reputation.
Its compatibility with warm soup
has always been excellent!
It's really delicious!
President, you're a genius.
Oh, stop it!
What do you think now, Shinomiya?
-Did you know that cold rice is delicious?
-It's so good.
You can make it your business!
-It's really a must-have experience!
-Kaguya!
Kaguya!
Kaguya, let's go home together!
I'm so happy to have a sleepover with you!
It doesn't hurt, but I still want to cry!
Goodbye, Fujiwara.
This is the end of our friendship.
She's looking even more disdainful now!
Just why is that?
Is that so? If she can act like that,
I have a few thoughts of my own.
Just you wait until tomorrow!
THE NEXT DAY
You put so much energy
into your lunch box today.
My chefs kind of got excited today.
It looks as delicious as usual.
That's right.
Then ask me, "Can I have a bite, please?"
If you do that, I will be so generous...
Give me, give me!
Well, then, let's exchange lunch boxes.
That's how I would give it to you.
Come now, ask me anytime.
Should we eat, too?
Yes, sure.
Wow, you have octopus-shaped
sausages today, too.
That's right, that's a staple food for me.
That's nice.
They're cute and tasty, they're the best!
Isn't that exaggerating it a bit?
No, they're good!
They're even tasty in my tummy!
I see, I see...
President.
Oysters are your favorite food, right?
Why does she have this disturbing aura
around her since yesterday?
Why is she offering me exquisite food
like this for no reason at all?
-She, surely, is up to something!
-Well, well.
What a cute lunch box you have there.
I am bestowing some charity upon you,
you pitiable president.
Is she pitying me?
How humiliating.
I won't have it.
I will definitely not have it.
If she gives me something that exquisite,
I can't give her anything in return.
-The sausages are so good!
-Kaguya?
Doesn't it hurt?
Is your head okay?
I have no choice but to hear her insults.
Never mind that, what's that thing?
Ah, this?
The president made this for me.
Making two lunch boxes
is really the same work as making one.
It's so tasty!
Is it? I'm glad.
Appearance is also important, right?
-That's true.
-Domestic animal disguised as human.
-A wretched parasite who relies on humans.
-It's delicious!
All that nutrition going to your heart
and not to your brain.
-What a disgusting animal.
-Thank you!
-I will never forgive you!
-Yummy.
Shinomiya is giving me a deathly stare.
Damn it!
Aren't the clubs meeting today?
I have to hurry up and eat.
No, the octopus-shaped sausage!
Well, then, I'm off!
What am I doing?
I'm an idiot.
Kaguya.
It's delicious, right?
Let's eat together.
Fujiwara, forgive me.
I was wrong about you.
You are truly a human being.
What did you think I was before that?
Have confidence.
-Today's result...
-I never doubted myself about being human!
Kaguya won due to Shirogane's retreat.
Good grief.
The president is giving me trouble.
He still won't come and confess to me,
even after I prepared everything.
Miss Kaguya.
Speaking hypothetically,
if you were to truly
fall in love with him,
would you wait for him to confess
like how you are doing it now?
Or would you go to him?
The battle of love and wits
is a fight of the spirit,
in which their dignity is at stake.
If a time like that came,
I would consider the risk
of him being taken away by someone
and evaluate rationally.
I would surely go and tell him.
Surely?
Absolutely.
Yes, surely.
Surely...
It's certainly not because she is ashamed
or she just can't confess her love,
or because she is afraid of rejection
or for some stupid reason like that.
This, I would like you to understand.
CONFESSION
Whatever, it doesn't matter!
Subtitle translation by Maria Carbune