The Shuchiin Middle School
is five minutes away
from the Shuchiin Academy on foot.
Due to that close distance,
many middle school students
who visit the Alumni Office
also visit the academy.
And on that day, one girl
is visiting the Student Council Room.
Yes?
I am sorry for bothering you.
What a cute visitor.
That was bad of me.
I shouldn't tell people to their face
that I think they're cute.
But for some reason, she captivated me.
I wonder why that is.
I am the accountant of the Middle School
Student Council, Kei Shirogane.
Kei Shirogane?
Shirogane...
This girl...
According to the rumors,
she is the president's sister!
She really is!
She has the same threatening eyes
and the same facial expression!
Well, come in.
Okay. Please, excuse me.
If you're looking for Shirogane,
he is in a meeting with the clubs
to discuss the budget.
I don't think he'll be back for a while.
A meeting with the club? Is that...
Back then, they said that the president
was impolite to them,
so it became difficult
for him to live in Japan.
That story is mostly embellished.
Was it a false rumor?
Of course.
It's just that his father
was transferred to work
in a country a little farther away.
So he was sent away?
I wonder if he already got used to
the thin air there?
Will he be all right?
His sister is anxious.
He will be okay.
On my honor as a Shinomiya, I will protect
the president in case anything happened.
Miss Shinomiya.
It's all right. Leave it to me.
If you want to shoot a general,
shoot his horse first.
If you want to take down a man,
entrap the ones around him first.
If you get along with his relatives,
you will get to hang out with his family,
then a more intimate interaction
can take place.
Right, Kaguya?
Oh, that would be good!
I will try to get her to call me "sister."
Then, what did you want to talk
to him about today?
I want to ask him to check the handouts
for the Student Council.
Then you can rely on me for that.
Even though I look like this,
I can do quite a lot.
The "Capable Woman" appeal!
By creating an image of competency,
she makes the other person respect her.
She is playing the part of a person
one would like to call "sister."
The calculations are correct,
but the commas are written wrongly.
And the layout
isn't exactly easy on the eyes.
You were here?
I see.
So I should make this part bigger
and fill in the blank space here?
By the way, you can
use macro for these parts.
I see.
You could group these lines...
It's hard to get close to someone
by playing the competent woman,
it could put a feeling of distance
between us.
We should be equals!
I should aim to have a relationship
so that we can hang out as friends.
And then...
Kaguya!
It's been so long,
please come to our place for lunch!
Oh, sure!
You get along well.
It's as if you were real sisters!
But we are real sisters!
Kaguya is already like a daughter to me!
Why don't you start living here with us?
Wonderful.
Kaguya was starving for family love.
Then, I...
Shirogane?
We are all Shirogane here,
so why don't you use our given names?
Then, Miyuki...
Kaguya...
Amazing!
Just how far can it go?
-You choose a form and a table...
-We could be friends!
-And choose the format from the form.
-A more intimate relation would be good!
Miss Shirogane,
would you like something to drink?
Yes.
Hello!
Oh, Kei!
Good kills today!
Good kills today to you, too!
What's up?
Did you come to have some fun?
No, I came here about work.
Fujiwara and Shirogane,
do you know each other?
That's right!
Kei is in the same year as Moe.
I am Moe, the third daughter.
Sometimes we have a sleepover at our place
and even though I am three years older,
it feels like we are regular friends.
-Right?
The other day we also played a video game.
Right?
We even made a dance for Kei.
Do you want to dance it here?
-What? It's embarrassing!
-You hid and did these things sneakily.
Is that how it is?
Now, I get it, this is how you are.
But Fujiwara is just a friend after all.
There's definitely nothing more than that!
Hey, sis!
What?
We are going shopping in Harajuku,
if you're free, would you like to come?
-I will, I will!
-Sister...
Window shopping in Harajuku would be nice!
Fujiwara...
is always snatching away
the things I want the most, like this.
That's greedy.
This kind of people will ruin the Earth.
They're the cancer of the Earth.
How repulsive.
Kaguya, will you come with us?
I will!
Oh, well. Fujiwara is a good girl.
I like that about her.
I hope we'll be friends forever!
How was the meeting today?
It was okay, somehow.
By the way,
did you come to our Student Council?
How was it?
How was what?
Well, as your big brother,
I worry about your behavior.
You're meddling and it's gross.
Well, Chika was the same as usual,
the accountant seemed gloomy
but he was nice to me.
And the vice president, Shinomiya...
I was nervous around her for some reason
and couldn't speak to her.
What did you say?
Shut up and die!
Today's result,
Shirogane Kei lost.
MOE, CHIKA, TOYOMI
The final exams are coming up soon, right?
Are you studying?
Fujiwara, don't whistle.
-There is no need to study for exams.
-What?
If you usually study properly,
you'll have no problem in the test.
What can last minute studying give you?
It just wears you down.
That is a lie.
Try your best to not
resort to cramming when studying.
This man even took time off
from his part-time job.
He has been pulling all-nighters
not just before the test,
but for the last ten days.
The final tests.
At Shuchiin Academy,
literature and math tests
are held five times a year.
Shirogane has won the first place
for the last three consecutive years
and consolidated his leading position
in the academics.
For Shirogane, an external student,
his grades are his greatest lifeline.
In order to keep his first place position,
he won't hesitate to use lies or tactics.
That's right.
Tests are supposed
to reflect your ability.
If you overstretch yourself
and get a good score,
you won't know your actual level.
That is a lie.
It's best to take the test
in a relaxed manner.
This woman is earnestly dealing
with something for a change.
For her, losing is not necessarily
a humiliation.
That's because she thinks that
getting defeated is part of life.
However, when it comes to studying,
her attitude is different.
Even after the genius Shinomiya
did her best,
she still couldn't beat Shirogane.
Shinomiya, who is
the personification of pride,
cannot accept this at all.
Ishigami?
If you don't push yourself a little,
your results will turn out bad.
If you get a failing mark again...
It's all right.
This time, I am studying for the test.
I will go home now and study.
That is a lie.
This man wants to quickly continue
playing the game he bought recently.
He has some nerve
to buy a game before the test.
He lives so recklessly,
it's as if he already guessed
the time of his own death.
And then he usually gets failing marks.
This is the way Yu Ishigami does things.
I don't know why I'm so bad in Japanese.
For foreign languages I use slang,
but that isn't enough for the test.
That's because you have a special way
of studying foreign languages.
Studying normally
might not be very efficient for you.
How much one studies
is not necessarily reflected
in the grades.
Not studying at all is also an option.
That is a lie.
That's right.
I don't study three days before the exam
and I just concentrate my mind
while in a meditation posture.
That works for me.
That is a lie.
I see. I understand!
I won't study!
She means it.
This girl has been dragged
into Kaguya and Shirogane's sabotage.
As a result, her grades are worsening.
100TH PLACE, 394 POINTS, NAKAMURA AKIHITO
AVERAGE
Her grades are average,
but her will to study is great.
Despite her personality,
Fujiwara is an excellent student.
This is precisely why...
she doesn't question the words
from her top two ranked friends.
She doesn't notice
that they are playing dirty.
The competition for the best result
begins before picking up the pen.
Using not only knowledge,
but also information,
personal connections,
and assets and all that implies,
is the natural choice.
The geniuses use up all their ingenuity
and fight an imaginary battle.
That is a final test.
197TH OUT OF 199 STUDENTS (1ST YEAR)
TEST DAY
I am nervous!
If my grades drop today,
they'll reduce my allowance.
Calm down. The test score
won't change if you panic now.
Aren't you nervous, President?
Of course not.
I believe in my ability.
I just have to use
what I've learned so far.
That is a lie.
This man is so nervous
that he feels like he could vomit.
He is already trembling so hard
that he cannot even hold his pen properly.
I definitely won't lose.
Nobody can know this but him.
The pressure of the king
doesn't compare
to that of the challengers.
Being always asked to be perfect
is a burden too heavy to bear alone.
What does it mean
to compete with a genius?
How much should you sacrifice for it?
For him, studying is the only weapon.
If the girl who can do anything
would beat him at studying as well,
she would become a person far away,
whom one can only look up to.
He has to win!
Start!
I will never lose!
In order to be on equal terms,
I won't lose to Shinomiya!
Well done, Shinomiya.
Sometimes it's also about luck.
You never know next time.
No, I also know how much
effort you put into it.
It's not about luck.
As I thought, I need to improve.
I am content with this result, too.
That is a lie.
This woman is so frustrated
that blood could spurt from her eyes.
If this weren't a public place,
she would stomp the ground
and roll around.
She was biting her lips
and keeping it all in.
Aren't you happy
with the results, President?
It's your fourth year in a row now.
No, the pressure this time
was just too big.
Actually, when all of this ends,
all I feel is relief.
I don't have any energy left
to be happy about it.
Is that how it is?
That is a lie.
-Did you see that, Shinomiya?
-This man is so happy that he is boxing.
Thus, the final exam
of lies and deceit is over.
There, there. It's all right.
Today's result,
Shirogane won.
EXAM RESULTS OF THE FIRST SEMESTER:
MIYUKI SHIROGANE 1ST PLACE TO 1ST PLACE
SHINOMIYA KAGUYA 2ND PLACE TO 2ND PLACE
Let's go back in time a little.
ONE WEEK BEFORE THE EXAM
Do you understand, Ishigami?
If you get any more failing grades,
you might fall back in school.
After all your hard work to get in,
isn't it a shame to waste it?
Anyway, make sure you don't fail
the next final test. Do you understand?
Yes.
Failing score.
At Shuchiin, the failing score
is less than the half
of the average grade.
There is no aid measure
like a makeup exam.
If you get a failing grade two times,
you fail the subject.
As soon as you fail
at a compulsory subject,
you repeat the year.
Ishigami has a yellow card
in three subjects.
If he gets another failing grade
he will have to repeat the year.
That's right.
-I was thinking of buying a game...
-Even though it could be terrible,
-That's how relaxed I am.
-he doesn't seem to sense the danger.
That was unbecoming
for a member of the Student Council.
If he falls behind, he won't be
the only who will one suffering.
It takes about five hours...
Ishigami.
Please come with me for a little.
What is it?
Is it something you can't do here?
Yes, we're going to be needing a place
where no one is around so we can be alone.
No!
No! That's scary!
-No!
-Why are you scared? Come here!
Because you want to do something
awful to me!
SUPPLY ROOM
I only did this
because you tried to run away!
If you didn't fight back,
I wouldn't have gotten rough with you.
You will do something terrible to me!
What do you want to do to me?
You already know, though.
Which situation you are in.
That's why...
After you make me endure
rigorous torture, you intend to kill me?
Or you might drive me mad
by doing something I hate.
Anyway...
Just please don't touch my games!
I will confiscate
your smartphone and games.
I did do something to displease her!
Now, she will thoroughly crush my spirit!
Please, stop.
Don't make me eat small fish...
-Or force me to study!
-Then, firstly...
Eat many of these dried sardines,
and solve all these problems.
Here you go, eat.
It's full of docosahexaenoic acid.
Acid? Will it dissolve
my internal organs slowly?
SEVERAL HOURS LATER
PROFICIENCY TEST
This is pretty awful.
But I caught a glimpse of his intelligence
in all important points.
Looks like it's worth educating you!
Let's study together at the same time.
On my honor as a Shinomiya,
I won't let you get a failing grade,
so be grateful.
Just what to you intend to do
to fix my head?
AVOIDING THE FAILING GRADE
Then, the special training continued
over several days.
As Ishigami tried to escape,
Kaguya would keep catching him
and before he knew it,
Ishigami lost the will to fight her.
LIBRARY
I think this reference book
is easier to understand.
Don't panic and consciously try
to understand it.
What do you want, though, really?
What are you saying?
I heard that if you get
another failing grade
you will fall behind for another year.
I am just making sure you
study enough to avoid that.
That's it?
Yes, that's it.
I don't believe you.
You care that much about me?
I wouldn't normally do this.
I would rather focus on my own test.
Then why?
That really is Shinomiya.
What? No way.
Miss Kaguya and Ishigami together?
Why?
It's just one of those things, right?
I don't like it!
I've had enough of this.
I think that I don't particularly care
if I fall behind.
Besides, I made a mess of things
in middle school,
and you just saw
how they treat me like a blister.
I was originally a problem pupil
who wouldn't go to school.
If people see you studying
with a person like me,
it might start weird rumors
that would damage your reputation.
Well, all the noise is annoying
and it gets in the way of studying.
You people!
You should keep quiet in the library.
Or maybe you have something
that you want to tell me?
Well, that Ishigami...
It's best not to get involved with him.
We just worry about you, Miss Kaguya.
Thank you for your warning.
However, I don't judge people
based on the opinions of those around me.
I decided that Ishigami is a person
worthy enough to have a relationship with.
Or are you doubting my judgment?
I am happy that you defended me,
but it will be badly misunderstood.
That doesn't concern us.
The most important thing now
is that you don't get a failing grade.
I don't care who might misunderstand what.
But...
I told you, didn't I?
I promised you on my honor
that I won't let you fail, no matter what.
Besides, without you,
the president would be troubled.
If you understand, move your hand.
Okay.
Somehow,
they didn't seem to need me at all.
STUDENT COUNCIL ROOM
The following day.
The tests are over!
Shinomiya, I somehow managed
to avoid failing the test.
I think I misunderstood you a little.
Ishigami.
What is this score?
You almost failed the test, didn't you?
After I took so much time to teach you!
I tried pretty hard.
How dare you drag my face through the mud!
It's hopeless!
This person is scary after all!
That's how Shinomiya is.
She doesn't lie to herself.
If she promises to do something,
consider it done.
She will do anything to keep her promise,
that's how much she cares.
I also thought she was ruthless
at the beginning,
but when you notice
that side of her, well...
What happened after that?
Forget about it.
It's an old story.
Today's result,
Shirogane lost.
LITTLE ISHIGAMI
Subtitle translation by Maria Carbune