Tonight...
Tonight, we're going
to the fireworks festival.
Even if Ms. Fujiwara is a nuisance,
I'll forgive her just for tonight.
She even cancelled her vacation
and asked me to go with her.
Summer vacation was really boring but...
We're all going together
for the first time.
You look just the same.
I'm going with the President
for the first time.
Instead of watching from my window,
I will get to see
the big fireworks up close.
That has been my dream.
Even though summer vacation was boring,
tonight is going to make everything
a good memory for me.
Have fun.
It was such a boring summer vacation...
You can't go.
Your recent behavior
has been unacceptable.
If you're in a crowd,
our security will lose sight of you.
If something happens to you,
I wouldn't know what to tell your father.
He wouldn't care at all.
"I'm really sorry."
I CAN NO LONGER GO TODAY I'M SORRY
Kaguya...
I want to see everyone.
I wish I didn't know about this.
If I hadn't known...
It would have been just another summer.
I wouldn't have to suffer so much.
But... I'll be okay.
Summer will come to an end.
I'll be okay.
MY NAME IS KAGUYA AND I'M A SOPHOMORE
AT SHUCHIIN ACADEMY
THIS IS MY FIRST TWEET
I WANT TO SEE FIREWORKS WITH EVERYONE
Got it.
THIS IS MY FIRST TWEET
I WANT TO SEE FIREWORKS WITH EVERYONE
Ms. Kaguya, how long
are you going to sulk in bed?
That's not like you.
Normally, you would've found a way
to sneak out of the house by now.
No matter how hard I try,
it never works out.
I can't even go shopping with my friends.
Father has no interest in me...
The President didn't even send me
an email this past month.
Nothing is working out for me!
Even if I sneak out now,
it will be pointless.
I'll never be able to see my friends.
No, you'll see your friends
when school starts
whether you like it or not.
Things go from bad to worse...
When she gets depressed,
she really goes to a dark place.
You're right.
This has been a rough summer for you.
But if you think about it, not being able
to see President Shirogane this summer
was actually the best choice.
The longer you don't see each other,
the deeper your love becomes.
The President is probably
feeling the same way as you right now.
Every day, he longs to see you.
He can't wait for the summer to end.
At the same time,
if both of you see each other
in the most dramatic way...
All of his accumulated desire...
Would explode all at once?
Yes, that's right.
You're looking like yourself again.
But there's two guards
watching over me today.
There's no way to escape
since I haven't planned for it.
Plans?
MUSEN TAXI
FOUR KINGS OF RAMEN
J. SUZUKI FROM KOENJI
Take me to Hamamatsucho.
Ms. Kaguya, dinner is ready.
I don't need any.
But...
I'm watching the fireworks.
Can't you at least let me watch it?
Very well.
Just kidding.
Now I know what's going on.
Ms. Kaguya?
She might be close by.
Fujiwara, wait there.
The phone you're calling
is either out of range or turned off.
I can't get through.
Is it the crowd?
Or is it because my phone is old?
Why?
You're trying to get
to the fireworks festival?
Traffic is bad because of street closures.
You might not make it in time.
I won't make it?
After everything that Hayasaka did for me?
No way!
Why doesn't anything seem to work?
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'll walk from here.
Be careful, young lady.
I will.
Our meeting spot is Takeshiba Wharf.
The main streets are crowded.
If I run through the back streets
I should make it just in time.
I'll be able to see them.
The first junior student I helped.
My first friend at school.
The first person I liked.
I have a circle of friends
that I'm a part of!
If I could watch the fireworks
with the people I like,
I couldn't be any happier.
What a wonderful experience that would be.
That's all I was thinking about
during the entire summer.
God...
This summer,
I don't need romance or love.
So...
Please, just let me be with my friends.
...has concluded.
Please, pick up your food, trash,
and beverages
before leaving the area.
I repeat.
Tonight's fireworks festival
has concluded.
Please, pick up your food, trash,
and beverages
before leaving the area.
I should have known.
God...
doesn't exist.
I wonder if everyone
enjoyed the fireworks.
I sure hope so.
I only got a glimpse of the
fireworks between the buildings.
But they were huge.
The fireworks that everyone saw
must have been beautiful.
If everyone had fun, then I'm satisfied.
I wish I could've seen...
the fireworks...
with everyone.
Then I'll show them to you.
President?
Come with me, Shinomiya!
If you want to see them so bad,
I'll show them to you.
How...
How did you know I was here?
You mean the "Guess What Shinomiya
Is Thinking and Find Her Game"?
It was 100 times easier than usual.
Kaguya!
President, I found us a cab.
It's the same girl!
Everyone, get in!
Driver,
take the freeway,
then get on the Aqua-Line to Umihotaru.
There's a fireworks festival
that was postponed until tonight
due to the rain.
President, are you thinking...
We're going to Chiba!
The fireworks in Kisarazu
ends at 8:30 p.m.!
Can we get to Chiba in 20 minutes?
I don't know.
But it's worth the risk.
Let's show some fireworks to Shinomiya!
I'm going to step on the gas a bit.
Don't tell anyone, okay?
Who is this cool driver?
FOUR KINGS OF RAMEN
J. SUZUKI FROM KOENJI
God, get us there on time!
President, I can't see anything outside.
The Aqua-Line is an underwater tunnel,
so you won't be able to see anything.
We're approaching the Umihotaru parking!
We're going to the surface!
Get us there on time!
Everyone watched the fireworks.
But, I'm sorry.
I couldn't take my eyes off...
his face.
My heart was beating so loud.
I couldn't even hear...
the fireworks.
FIRST DAY OF THE NEW SEMESTER
The first day of the new semester.
All the students have mixed emotions
about going back to their daily routine.
At the end of an uneventful
and long summer vacation,
they all experienced something
that was memorable.
STAKE OUT SPOT 6 HOURS BEFORE FIREWORKS
FIND SHINOMIYA GO TO KISARAZU BY CAB
Shirogane looked back on his efforts.
Then I'll show them to you.
He was dying from regret!
You mean the "Guess What Shinomiya
Is Thinking and Find Her Game"?
That is so embarrassing!
I'm such a dork!
A dark past.
Since he barely got to see Kaguya
during the summer vacation,
when he saw Kaguya
on the night of the fireworks,
-he was in a state of euphoria.
-I found her!
-Being in a euphoric state,
-Then I'll show them to you.
-he blurted out cringy lines.
-"Guess What
Shinomiya Is Thinking and Find Her Game."
It was 100 times easier than usual.
I don't know.
But it's worth the risk.
For the next ten years,
this dark memory will haunt him
every time he remembers it.
If I see Shinomiya now...
I don't know what to say but...
what you said that night was...
How can I put it?
You sounded really narcissistic.
President...
What you said was really cringy.
Somebody, please kill me!
Looking forward to the new semester!
Hi, Fujiwara...
And Shinomiya...
STUDENT COUNCIL ROOM
She's ignoring me.
She thinks I'm so cringy
that she can't even look at me!
Shinomiya, the other night...
-I totally messed up.
-There's dust here.
She thinks that I'm so cringy
that she doesn't even want to be near me.
False.
Kaguya is ignoring Shirogane.
But not because she doesn't like him.
On the contrary,
she is acting like that
because she is shy and nervous.
It's commonly known
as "ignoring your crush."
Why am I avoiding him?
That would actually mean...
I have feelings for the President!
I have to talk to him...
Like how we used to talk
before the summer.
I need to regain Shinomiya's trust.
Act natural and cheerful.
First, I have to say hi to her...
They are walking straight
towards each other.
They should easily be able
to talk to each other.
However...
Fujiwara, you should clean
the floor first.
Oh, you're right.
There's dust...
I can't speak to her.
I'll clean up over here.
...they muster up
the courage to try again!
But the results are still the same.
Oh, no. The closer I get to him,
the more I can't look at his face!
How can I talk to her?
The way they barely miss each other,
is similar to the dogfights
of fighter aircrafts.
Passing each other twice isn't normal.
Is this a coincidence?
I understand now.
He's shy.
If that's the case, there's no need
for me to be embarrassed.
I'm calm.
I can do this.
This time, I won't fail.
I can talk to her!
An asterisk!
Fujiwara, are you making fun of me?
Focus on cleaning the room!
I don't understand the rules of this game?
I have to talk to her
and clear up this misunderstanding!
I won't fail!
That's it!
It's not an asterisk.
What's up?
It's delta!
What are you thinking?
Are you making fun of me, too?
What did I do?
You don't get it, do you?
Why does everyone despise me
all of a sudden?
Ishigami, you think
I'm pathetic don't you?
President, you too?
I'm sorry.
I don't know what's going on,
but I'm going home.
Ishigami, shot down.
Too bad, but he shouldn't have interfered.
Fujiwara, don't interfere with us either.
Why me?
Fujiwara, shot down.
Why is everyone bothering us?
I can see why I might avoid her.
But why would Shinomiya ignore me?
Maybe...
She has feelings for me?
Stay calm.
Just close your eyes.
Maybe she doesn't think I'm cringy,
and she thinks I'm cool?
Shirogane regains confidence.
I'm going to do it!
I can do it.
I have something
I want to tell you, President.
President, the night of the fireworks...
I have to say...
Thank you.
Well...
I wanted to say...
President, the night of the fireworks...
Cringy.
You're so cringy.
You're...
You're right!
Shirogane, shot down.
President!
I want to tell you something!
I know what you want to say!
Please, wait up, President!
Things are back to normal.
TODAY'S RESULT,
SHINOYIMA IS THE TOP SHOOTER
The second semester has begun.
Romantic battle of the minds.
A battle between a boy and a girl
who are too proud to confess their love.
They can't say how they feel,
so they continue to hope.
That the other one confesses their love.
I'm going to do everything
to make you say...
that you love me.
Subtitle translation by Hashim Bharoocha