Meow!
Is that all right?
It's so cute!
The cat ears are on Fujiwara's time,
Shinomiya is on mine.
That's right!
In other words,
the time you brought was originally
just for Shinomiya and the cat ears.
I'm scared!
Cat ears and a little girl.
It's a symbiosis.
These things were born into the world
in order to be joined together.
Like the clover and the honeybee.
A crocodile and a hummingbird.
Avocado and soy sauce.
And then, the cat.
Majority of humans like cats.
And then we have here,
a girl with an attractive face and figure,
Kaguya Shinomiya.
How did he realize the compatibility
between the two living beings?
-She's cute!
-Marriage!
Is cosplay really necessary
for the welcome party?
Yes!
After Japan, France is the country
where cosplay is popular.
When doing cosplay,
you don't need any words.
This is the best strategy
to break language barriers
and deepen our friendships.
But...
What do you think, President?
-She's cute!
-Marriage!
That's right.
-It's all right.
-She is so cute.
This is not good.
When I look at Shinomiya,
my face gets too enthusiastic.
I need to calm down
and look at her normally.
Your face is scary!
His reaction is weak.
In the end, these clothes
don't look good on me.
-People with charm like Fujiwara
-What's wrong?
-should wear this.
-What?
You should also endure it, President.
Meow!
How do I put it?
Well, it's not so good.
She's not being frank.
Did she completely understand?
This can't look good on me.
It's good!
So cute!
Marriage!
What?
He just put cat ears on!
No matter what others think,
it looks perfect in Kaguya's mind.
What should I do?
I can't stop smiling.
If I don't stop, they will see
that I think he looks cute
What's wrong, Shinomiya?
Now that it has come to this...
Nothing at all.
The trick of biting your lip.
But that is also not perfect.
She is still left with half a smile.
What's with that face, Shinomiya?
Do you have a problem with my cat ears?
No, no way.
It looks...
very good on you.
That facial expression.
It's like looking at an insect.
It's as if it looks so bad on me,
that I don't qualify as a human.
Fujiwara, let's take a picture
of the President.
That's a good idea!
Let's save this image
for future generations.
That is a blackmail expression.
She wants to use this as a threat
or a bargaining chip someday.
I absolutely won't allow it!
Don't say that.
-Now you, Kaguya!
-Me, too?
Shinomiya, too?
If she takes a picture,
they will see my weakness.
But...
at the same time, I will legally get
a picture of this cute living being.
The two choices hang in balance.
Pros and cons weigh just as much.
TWO ALTERNATIVES
Take proper pictures, Fujiwara!
Shirogane chose to preserve the cuteness.
That's a choice he would
normally never make.
Well...
take it with 4,000 pixels, please.
Okay!
She's even cuter up close. Damn it!
My face muscles grow stiff!
It looks so good on him!
No, my mouth is smiling again.
You two...
smile more cheerfully, please.
-Not possible.
-I can't.
I want to see
how cute he is from up close.
I want to go closer and burn this image
into my memory.
Why are you looking
into each other's eyes?
You two!
If you are going to fight,
I am confiscating these!
Just now, what were we doing?
What was that compulsive feeling?
That was scary.
-Cat ears are scary!
Today's result,
Secretary Fujiwara lost.
NO WEARING OF CAT EARS
FOR STUDENT COUNCIL MEMBERS
Meow!
The welcome party is on Monday next week.
Apart from setting up,
we need to buy souvenirs
and Japanese sweets.
Two people have to go shopping, right?
We'll also need general goods,
and there will be many participants,
so the quantity needed is great.
So we need to give up
our free day for shopping?
What a bothersome task.
Oh, what a hassle.
Who would want to do it?
Right, Shinomiya?
That's right.
If nobody wants to go,
it will be a problem.
Well, if it's really necessary,
I don't mind that much.
So should we play a game
and the loser has to go shopping?
-A game?
Yes!
The bad words game.
Yes.
This is an example.
You write the word on a note like this
and give it to the person on the right.
Please hold it up
so that you can't read it.
If the person says that word, they lose.
I see.
So you don't know what
the forbidden word is.
It's simple.
You just lost.
All right, let's play.
You give it to the person on the right.
Then I should write...
a word that Fujiwara would use.
But...
the two people who will lose
will go shopping.
Well, a man is needed for carrying things
and nobody can beat Shinomiya in knowledge
about Japanese traditional sweets.
In the end, it's all about efficiency.
In that case, I have to let Fujiwara win
and defeat Shinomiya.
FIRST PLACE
FUJIWARA
There is no way Fujiwara
would say this word.
I won this game!
Are we ready to play?
Yo, we're starting right now, yo!
Secretary Fujiwara?
The game words are derived from
words I usually use
I can't take it, yo!
That's why I changed
my speaking style, yo!
Too bad, man!
No!
Don't look!
-Yo! Yo!
-This is bad.
She doesn't usually say "check it out."
Kaguya, what do you think
is your word, yo?
Say "ho!"
Say "ho"?
Yikes, she's acting so adult!
In this game,
there is a surefire way to win.
That is to not speak at all.
Say "yes."
-Shinomiya.
-Yes?
The game won't progress
if you're like that.
At least talk the minimum
necessary to maintain a conversation.
I have no choice, right?
I understand.
"Inevitable behavior."
Each person will act in a certain way.
If you create a certain situation,
it will generate a corresponding behavior.
That's the gist of the game.
However,
how will I make her say that word?
I've been trying to make her say
that for half a year.
I lack the ability for it.
Well,
I should just get her talking
about things she likes.
Secretary Fujiwara,
is there something you don't like?
Shirogane passed the topic
of dislike to Fujiwara,
a word easy to connect with "like."
Something that I dislike?
There are things, yes.
People often tell me
I can't read a situation.
Some people also say
that it has its advantages.
But they don't include me
when they talk about romantic feelings.
They say I always step on landmines!
That is a sound assessment.
When I think I might cause trouble
for people without knowing it,
I get very sad.
So that is something I dislike.
Fujiwara.
Nobody thinks you cause trouble.
There are many people
who rely on your frankness.
Kaguya.
Really?
You don't hate me, Kaguya?
What? No, of course, I...
like you.
I win, yo!
LIKE
Inevitable behavior.
In the end, it was inevitable
for kind Kaguya
to try and comfort a troubled Fujiwara.
Fujiwara interpreted this correctly.
Amazing!
That was wicked.
Was all you just said a lie?
Not a lie, but a bluff, yo!
There's no way people wouldn't tell me
about their romantic feelings, yo!
The rest is easy with this result.
If I let my guard down
and follow her lead,
I will automatically lose.
Everything she needs
for winning is achieved
However...
-Was that really a bluff?
-Rain falling!
-In every bluff...
-Spears are falling!
-you can hide a morsel of truth.
-It's nice to be so carefree!
If that is so, how much of it is a lie?
Are Fujiwara's words
about feeling alienated
and her eyes just lying?
If there is even a slightest possibility,
it is wrong to lose on purpose.
I don't believe in hurting others
for the sake of your own good.
This is part of my moral code.
Prioritizing my own circumstances
and losing on purpose...
That would also be pursuing my gain
and alienating her.
Going shopping with Shinomiya
might be wonderful,
but I...
I can't betray my personal conviction.
Secretary Fujiwara.
From now on, I will be playing seriously.
Boom, yo!
I did it! I even beat the president! Yes!
Inevitable behavior.
An individual will react
to a certain situation
in a characteristic way.
And being able to predict that
is the gist of the game.
So we're going shopping, right?
Well, we lost, so there's no helping it.
The bad words game
is a game to find out
how much you understand one another.
Oh, damn it! I was beaten.
We'll go buy some souvenirs.
-I am looking forward to it.
-Today's result,
Shirogane totally lost.
"Check it out"?
The President said we will talk
about shopping after school.
I see.
The day he bought a smartphone,
we exchanged mail addresses
and telephone numbers.
But I've been waiting for so long,
and he hasn't contacted me at all!
It seems like he doesn't want
to be the first to write to me!
"President, I'm looking forward..."
What are you doing?
Well, I thought
you should contact him instead.
No way!
I can't send it first!
That's a bit dull.
Miss Kaguya.
Do you like President Shirogane?
Well, I think of him without disdain.
I see.
But...
I just think that
he has some qualities that I lack
that's why I'm interested in him.
It's not a romantic feeling at all.
So, if the little secretary
and Shirogane were to date?
What is it?
You're wrong!
I just don't want to lose Fujiwara
to the President.
She's my precious friend.
LOOK, A LIVE OCTOPUS!
A precious friend, right?
If you really care so much about it,
Miss Kaguya,
don't write to him, call him.
Call him?
He thinks he will receive a message.
Take advantage of his negligence
and attack first.
Negligence?
Attack first?
It's a perfect plan.
Before Miss Kaguya starts arguing
for argument's sake,
I press click and...
Here you go!
Wait a second! I'm not braced for it!
CALLING
Yes?
This is Shinomiya.
Is that you, President?
I am Miyuki's father.
Well...
By the way, is Mr. Shirogane home?
I am also called Shirogane.
Not you.
I mean, is Mr. Miyuki home?
Oh, my son?
Miyuki!
There's a girl on the phone!
What? A girl is calling my brother?
Hey!
Don't just answer people's phones
whenever you like, Dad!
It's me.
Oh, it's Shinomiya.
Oh, Shinomiya?
I just called regarding
the matter of tomorrow.
Is now a good time?
I am in the bathtub, but it's okay.
In the bathtub?
That means he's naked.
Miss Kaguya, you are now talking to
-a completely naked man.
-Is the sound muffled?
I will call you again later.
No, it's all right.
My smartphone is waterproof.
No, it's not all right.
Can we meet in front of Hachiko
at 11:00 a.m. tomorrow?
Yes.
We will buy the sweets and go to Hands.
That's about it, right?
Yes.
EXTEND THE CONVERSATION
See you tomorrow, then.
Okay.
Oh, Shinomiya...
What?
What was he going to say?
I'm going to sleep already.
WHAT I WANTED TO SAY WAS THAT
IT MIGHT BE COLD TONIGHT,
SO KEEP WARM AND SLEEP WELL
I'm glad you had your first message.
Today's result, Kaguya won.
THE NEXT DAY
It seems Shibuya Station was flooded.
I'm going.
The President is waiting for me.
I have to go!
There is no way he is coming.
"A cancellation message."
Oh well, at least,
it's the first message from Shinomiya.
Then, shall I call it a day?
I'm glad my smartphone is waterproof.
THE END OF THE NERVE-WRACKING
SHOPPING TRIP
IT TOOK 30 MINUTES TO WRITE
THE CANCELLATION MESSAGE.
WELCOME PARTY
We made it!
Thank you for your hard work, everybody!
Principal, please stop giving us
last minute notices.
I understand.
Then, have fun, everybody!
Can you speak French, Shinomiya?
No, I'm not very good at it.
How about you?
How are you, mademoiselle?
My name is Miyuki Shirogane.
As expected of the president.
I just learned some lessons
from the handbook quickly.
Bonjour!
Thank you very much
for your invitation today.
We would like to thank you
for coming this far.
We will do our best to make sure that
you are left with a lasting memory
of your stay with us.
Thank you very much.
Liar!
The majority of Japanese content
is focused on the domestic market.
-Japan hasn't discovered a way yet...
-Hey, you can speak French?
Yes.
My mother used to be a diplomat,
so she drilled several foreign languages
into my mind since I was a child.
Wait a minute.
Am I the only one here
who can't speak French?
Complete isolation.
What should I do?
If it's found out that I am the only one
who can't speak it...
The President
of the Japanese High School Council
can't speak French?
Maybe he is stupid, right?
How cute.
It's no use. My chest hurts.
Shirogane.
Why do you think I had you organize
this party suddenly?
I had to make sure you are worthy enough
for me to entrust this school to you.
Now, the real test begins.
Betsy.
Yes.
No need to hold back.
Please chop up that Shirogane boy
with all of your strength.
Are you sure?
The French High School
Student Council Vice President,
Beltoise Betsy.
The girl is called
"The Wounds-Licking Razor"
No one has ever survived
her verbal attacks.
Bonjour.
Betsy charges on him with sarcasm
that levels a punch in the head.
Yes.
Next, she provokes him as if insulting
his parents and lover at the same time.
Yes.
Additionally,
a character assassination that would make
60-year-old men break down in tears.
Exactly.
Miyuki Shirogane!
Responding to that dreadful attack
just by keeping a smile on your face...
If it were me, I would already be bowing
on the ground in my own vomit.
You could almost think that
-he doesn't understand what she says.
-Exactly!
My attack isn't working.
That's impossible!
Betsy shouts severe insults at him.
Yes.
You son of a...
What did you just say?
Oh, forgive me.
You don't understand Japanese?
Kaguya threatens Betsy with a language
that could get her in trouble
with the Broadcasting Code.
Shinomiya?
President?
It's not what you think.
She is going to kill me!
I am sorry.
Are you all right?
Japanese high school girls are scary.
Oh, what have I done?
Today's result,
the Japanese school has won.
You despise me now, don't you?
After talking so foul...
That was just like the old me.
Like I told you,
I only know a few French phrases.
I couldn't make out your words.
That's why I don't know what you said.
But...
I understood that
you were mad at her for insulting me.
Thank you.
President?
That quality of yours is...
I think.
What?
What did you say?
It's a secret.
Hey, don't be like that.
I want to know!
A secret is a secret.
-What did you say?
-Today's result...
-It wasn't in French.
-they both won.
-Was it Yiddish?
-No.
Was it Finnish?
Subtitle translation by Maria Carbune