When you fall in love with someone,
you confess your love
and it'll be accepted.
Anyone would tell you
that it's a wonderful thing,
but everything is wrong about that!
Love is a war!
The moment you fall in love, you lose.
STUDENT COUNCIL ROOM
Hey.
LOVE RIVALS
What is this?
The principal just confiscated it
from a student.
It's an educationally damaging book,
so he told me to dispose of it.
Really now.
He could have done it himself.
A book with damaging content?
DISORDER
Disorder!
NOT DISORDER,
DEBAUCHERY
They meant "obscenity!"
This country is falling into debauchery.
Why is she panicking like that?
-Was it a pornographic book?
-Shirogane showed a deep interest.
-What is this?
-Kaguya, don't look!
A survey on when people had
their first time.
Thirty-four percent of them
said "before high school."
That's a lie!
There's no way people are doing that.
Thirty-four percent!
In other words, a third!
In a class of thirty people,
ten are experienced.
Of these three people,
there is a high possibility
that one of them has had sex.
The percentage is so high because all
the people answering the questions
are people who read books like these.
That's a sample selection bias.
There is no way so many people
are experienced in reality.
Right?
Is that so?
I think it's an appropriate ratio.
It's actually a little small.
Um...
I couldn't believe it to be true,
but have you already
experienced that, Kaguya?
Yes, a long time ago.
Is the code for Aomori Area 017?
That's surprising.
When people become high school students
they are already experienced?
But they mostly grew up in an environment
that lacks love and affection.
-It might be good for me...
-The area code for Oshamanbe is...
-...to get a boyfriend soon.
-...013.
-My father won't forgive me, though.
-Kaguya noticed their impatient reactions.
When people compare themselves
and notice they got a late start,
they panic.
And through this impatience,
they are driven by the feeling
that they should get a partner soon.
In other words...
Am I too late
to experience that kind of things?
I AM LATE?
I NEED A GIRLFRIEND
SHINOMIYA, PLEASE DATE ME!
Shinomiya, please go out with me!
He will confess to me!
Kaguya has already decided
on her plan for the day.
What stupid talk.
So, President, are you doubting
if you are truly popular with the girls?
She stirs him up.
Don't you have a girlfriend?
She stirs him up!
Oh, that's right.
I don't have a relationship
with a special someone.
Not now, at least.
"Not now!" That implies that he had
a girlfriend a while ago,
but since, in fact, he never dated anyone,
it's also not a lie, so it's a
very convenient word choice.
This word is loved across the world
by young and elderly people alike.
So, Miyuki Shirogane doesn't have
any romantic experiences.
But it's not like Shirogane
isn't popular at all.
I would actually say he is very popular.
Perhaps we should just say
that birds of a feather flock together
or consider that strange people
are attracted to strange people?
Because he tends to only
attract dangerous people,
he has never had a romantic relationship.
Why am I popular among such people?
Therefore, because of his
lack of experience in such things,
he developed a strong self-confidence
based on the fact that he is popular.
They are surely attracted
to my overflowing intelligence.
Should I feel guilty?
-Men like him with endless confidence...
-Not now...
-...and a chaste purity,
-...at least.
made him into what he is today which is...
Not now, at least.
the monster virgin.
-But the weakness of that monster...
-Of course, they have experience.
There's no changing the fact
that he's a virgin.
Lying is the simplest thing to do,
but to tell someone experienced
that you also have experience
is as reckless as a movie amateur
trying to trick a movie maniac
that he knows a lot about movies.
Even if I were to lie like that,
I do it all the time!
Are you boasting about it?
Were you afraid that people would find out
about your chaste travels?
How cute of you.
She would definitely find out.
Well, if I felt like it,
I'd get a girlfriend anytime...
He hangs on as strong as he can.
Is that so?
I thought since you have a little sister,
you must be doing it with her
all the time.
That is...
No way!
Are you an idiot?
Well, you are family.
I did it all the time
with my newborn nephew.
I also filmed it.
You're crazy!
I miss it, to be honest.
It won't do, you know.
To fear human contact that much.
This is also the bewilderment
of the current society.
No, it's you!
You are the bewilderment of the nobility!
What is so strange?
Fujiwara does it with pets all the time.
Do you?
I don't! Don't get involved, please!
Is the Shinomiya family's
educational course this wrong?
What I held for common sense
is something she has no clue about?
Shinomiya.
I want to ask you just in case,
do you know what it means
when they say "it's your first time?"
Don't make fun of me, please.
I know what the "first time" means.
It's when you kiss someone.
Good grief.
Kaguya Shinomiya.
As the eldest daughter of the family,
for the past 16 years, since infantry,
she was kept away from sexual education.
All she knows about sex ends with kissing.
THE END
Beyond that, her awareness
is at the level of those urban legends.
The stork doesn't have
anything to do with it, right?
She's an extremely sheltered girl.
Of course, she has no way of knowing
what the "first time" is.
Shinomiya.
President, I'll take it from here.
Kaguya.
What they mean here with
"the first time" is...
They do... that.
Then they take off their underwear...
and then they... like beasts...
16 MINUTES LATER
But...
that kind of thing is only legal
when you're married!
I thought my heart stopped.
TODAY'S RESULTS. SHINOMIYA LOST.
Today's results,
Shinomiya lost.
Shirogane.
I don't approve of intercourse.
Would you do it alone, please?
It's a quiet night.
That's true.
It's Fujiwara's turn to walk Pes today,
so she went home earlier.
Pes! Pes!
And Ishigami, the accountant,
came and went out of here at some point.
He should simply get a prize
for having perfect attendance, right?
Compared to earlier,
you are much rounder now, Shinomiya.
Do you mean I got fat?
No, I meant your personality.
Don't go saying something corny.
That's right.
I made an effort to be liked by
people a little more.
Was that it?
I wonder if I came to understand
what kind of person you are.
You mean if you know me?
Really?
It's been six months since we started
working together in the Student Council.
I thought the work itself
made me know you.
If that's so, let's put it to the test.
A test?
Yes, to see how much you understand me.
Let's try it out.
Do you know the 20 questions game?
The 20 questions game.
-The one asking the question can ask...
-Size of a palm?
-...20 times to find out the answer...
-Yes.
But you can only ask
questions answerable by yes or no.
If they find out what it is
with 20 questions, the person wins.
If they can't,
the person being asked wins.
But you can determine most answers
if you get to ask 20 questions.
If you truly understand me,
you should be able to find out
by only asking 10 questions.
I see.
I am okay with that.
Are you ready?
Yes.
Then, the first question is...
One, is it something I can touch?
Yes. It's not a word or an idea.
Two. Is it an electronic device?
Three. Is it something
that can be warm or cold?
From her last answer, I can deduce that
it's either a living being,
food, hot water or ice,
an open fire,
or a temperature control device.
But this is a test of how much
I understand Shinomiya.
The answer is something
that has to do with her.
If that's the case...
Four. Is it something you possess?
Five. Is it something you touched today?
Six. Is it something you have at home?
So far there were three consecutive "no."
I thought it was something she owned,
but I got confused.
I should dig around her psyche
a little bit more.
Then it's...
Seven. Is it something you like?
Yes.
What's with that expression?
It's like she's a little embarrassed,
a little bashful.
Don't tell me...
Eight. Is it a living being?
Yes.
Is it...
Is it me?
Calm down a little. Let's confirm it.
You can touch it.
It's not an electric device.
It doesn't have a constant temperature.
She doesn't possess it.
She didn't touch it today.
It's not in her house, of course.
All the conditions are met.
Then, something that Shinomiya likes...
Is this an indirect confession of love?
Nine. What do you mean by "like"?
As friends or people or something else?
I can't answer that.
It's not answerable by yes or no.
Damn it!
I panicked and wasted a question.
Calm down.
It's still possible
that she means someone else.
Then...
Ten.
Is it someone smart and handsome,
with blond hair, and well-defined eyes?
Is that it?
It's me!
Who she means is me! It's definitely, me.
Good grief, Shinomiya.
That's one twisted love confession.
So many things happened so far.
That's right.
Each time I tried to understand
her as a person.
To understand...
What?
Then, are you done with the questions?
You can tell me the answer.
That's how it was.
Do I understand at all
what kind of person Shinomiya is?
During times like this,
Shinomiya always...
The answer is...
a dog.
Damn.
That's the correct answer.
Accurately put, it's Pes, Fujiwara's dog.
So, shall we go back?
PESU (SMILE)
It's already late, right?
That's right.
Today's test results are...
success.
BECAUSE SHIROGANE UNDERSTOOD SHINOMIYA'S
PERSONALITY SOME WAY OR ANOTHER.
PES IS REALLY SIMILAR TO HIM
Kaguya Shinomiya, the eldest daughter
of the Shinomiya group.
Which is a part of an old financial group.
Her life was decided for her
since she was born,
or rather, even before she was born.
For example...
Two thousand, five hundred
and seventy-four times.
The number of times she watched through
the window while being driven to school.
SHINOMIYA
However, on that day...
Is it a cat?
Yes.
She got inside the engine room.
I am arranging for another car, so
please wait for a little while.
If that's the case, I will walk today.
At least, go with Hayasaka, please.
Well, I don't really mind...
If she had to wait for me to change,
she would be late for school,
so I think it's best for her to go alone.
See? Even Hayasaka thinks so.
I'll be all right.
Miss Kaguya!
See you later!
Under the lively sun,
her breathing gets a little livelier.
Well...
I might not get another chance
to walk to school.
I have to use this precious occasion.
If that's so...
the president is
cycling from Setagaya or so.
Then he would come via Meiji street.
He always gets to school a little late,
so if I wait by the bridge, surely...
Well,
if I don't hurry up, I'll miss him.
What's wrong?
If you have a problem,
tell me about it quickly and concisely.
Pedestrian... crossing...
The pedestrian crossing?
Okay, then, let's cross it together.
You can let go of my hand now.
There are many pedestrian crossings
on the way to school.
So...
how have you been
getting to school so far?
We go to school in groups.
Yeti always holds my hand usually.
The snowman?
He has a home made of ice,
so that's why we call him Yeti.
But I'm in the sixth grade now,
so we can't go in a group.
That's why I am alone.
She thinks entirely like a third grader.
When I was her age,
I was more put together.
I am alone.
I wish we were all together!
Hey, there.
Just because you don't
go to school in a group,
it doesn't mean you have to go alone.
You can tell your friends to meet you
or wait for you or go to meet them.
Wouldn't it be nice to go together?
Right?
You're smart!
Are you a genius?
Something like that.
Mikiti!
Yeti!
Then, you're okay now, right?
Go!
Bye-bye, genius girl!
Good morning. You surprised me!
Good morning! You surprised me, too!
-Let's go to school together!
-Okay.
By the way, where am I now?
It's 8:25 AM.
I am late.
If they found out I was late,
they won't ever let me
go to school alone again.
One time was enough for me.
I just wanted to see how it's like.
I wish I could go to school with someone.
President?
Shinomiya?
What are you doing here?
The classes are about to start!
You too, President. Don't tell me you...
I never was.
I was never late at one time in my life.
More than that, you're
the problem, Shinomiya!
If you walk, you will surely be late!
You can't be late as a member
of the Shuchiin Student Council!
Climb on my back.
We're going!
If being late is bad,
the two of us on the bike would be...
Shut up!
School regulation takes precedence
over the Road Traffic Act for us!
The next day,
Kaguya was being driven to school
as usual, but...
Can we go?
-Yes!
-There are times...
when she would smile while remembering it.
Subtitle translation by Maria Carbune