The treasurer of the four-member
student council at Shuchiin Academy...
Yu Ishigami.
The man who is indispensable
to the student council,
yet hasn't made
much of an impression on them.
The man Shirogane,
the president of the student council,
chose to be the treasurer
based on expectations of his prowess.
Here's this month's financial report.
Great.
He has been biding his time...
What is it?
I want to quit the student council.
...waiting for the chance
to resign from the student council!
I see. Quit the student council...
YU ISHIGAMI WANTS TO LIVE
You've got to be kidding me!
Without you, we'll go bankrupt!
I'm begging you here!
Yu Ishigami.
He's a data processing expert.
At Shuchiin Academy,
only the president is elected.
PRESIDENT
MIYUKI SHIROGANE
VICE-PRESIDENT
KAGUYA SHINOMIYA
SECRETARY
CHIKA FUJIWARA
TREASURER
YU ISHIGAMI
The other members are appointed
based on their abilities.
Yu Ishigami is a talented person
who was scouted by the student council...
despite the fact that he had barely begun
his first year there.
Normally he takes his work home
and only shows up
in the student council room for meetings,
but he is a full-fledged council member.
Undeniably, Yu Ishigami is the treasurer
of Shuchiin Academy's student council.
And now he is trying to quit his post.
But I've got an important reason.
That reason is...
What reason?
I think I'm going to be murdered.
Murdered?
I think Shinomiya-senpai
is going to kill me.
Shino...
O-On what basis do you think that?
Her eyes.
Eyes?
People's eyes are organs
that are connected directly to the brain.
Normally half of the brain
is used to process the sense of sight.
The movement of eyes can show
what someone is cautious about or hungry for.
Those organs clearly reveal
the brain's activity.
FOOD > CAT
GLUTTON
DOG > FOOD
SCAREDY-CAT
I can tell five or six percent of a person's
true character just by looking into their eyes.
That's not much!
I can probably do the same!
The way Shinomiya-senpai
looks at me sometimes...
I'm positive that the intent to kill
is in that glance.
What exactly happened?
It was a month ago.
COFFEE BLEND
FREE TICKET
But a lot of people think
that's the best way to kill time.
What is this?
I don't really go to coffee shops.
They're too expensive for my blood.
You have a point.
If there was a coupon or something,
it would be different.
PAT PAT
Yeah.
If it were cheaper,
I wouldn't mind going once in a while.
Not a word to anyone about those tickets.
What happened?
She threatened me, so I can't tell you.
Threatened?
I have a feeling
she's killed two or three people already.
What happened?
And then last week, too...
Shinomiya-senpai,
are you in love with the president?
FSSST
In love with the president?
Don't talk nonsense!
That would never happen!
You don't see him as a love interest?
N-No!
Of course not.
Really?
In fact, rumors like that are a nuisance!
Is that right?
I thought they'd make a good couple.
Then I'll give the president a hint
that you have no romantic interest.
YANK YANK
You'll tell him no such thing!
You hear me?
I think she has the skills
of a trained assassin.
A trained assassin?
Using the corner of a couch
to strangle me... That's a pro!
What do you think Shinomiya is?
SHIVER SHIVER
My guess is she's a natural-born serial killer.
I can see it in her eyes.
You put too much faith
in that five or six percent!
Fujiwara-senpai's
in even more danger than me.
Sometimes Shinomiya-senpai stares
at her as if she's less than human.
I estimate she's got
another two months left.
You calculated her life expectancy?
Ridiculous!
No, that type
is the most dangerous predator.
President...
Is Ishigami here?
I was at a meeting.
Don't make it worse for yourself!
It was about the budget
for the drama club.
Turn yourself in, Shinomiya!
Please!
Listen when someone's talking to you!
BEND BEND
I told you I was helping
the drama club, remember?
Today was the costume fitting.
O-Oh.
Still, you didn't need
to bring that prop in here.
Um, I just wanted
to tease you a little with it.
Sorry.
Cute.
Shirogane-senpai, this is a trap.
She's playing it cute
so you'll let your guard down.
D-Don't scare me like that!
That's just a costume!
Shinomiya hasn't killed anyone!
President!
Help.
Miss Kaguya killed me!
Then it's true!
What's true?
She's just wearing special makeup!
Oh, right!
No, President. This is a trap, too.
I suspect she really is dead,
but Shinomiya-senpai performed
some mad-science surgery on her.
Ishigami...
You always let imagination
get the better of you.
Shinomiya would never murder a soul.
Try to have more faith in your colleagues.
Okay?
Faith in my colleagues...
Anyway, that's impressive.
I know, right?
How is that attached?
It's like this. See?
Sorry I asked.
Faith in my colleagues...
Ishigami...
About our secret...
I appreciate that you've kept it to yourself.
Being tight-lipped is a virtue, right?
If you had blabbed...
Faith!
STAB
...this wouldn't be a toy.
Also, don't put the president in a bind.
Please don't say
anything more about resigning.
Do you want to try
stabbing me, President?
Then was she...
Can I? I wanted to try it once.
listening the whole time?
RESULTS OF TODAY'S MATCH:
ISHIGAMI LOSES
Results of today's match...
WANTS TO QUIT BECAUSE
HE'S AFRAID OF KAGUYA
BUT CAN'T QUIT BECAUSE
Ishigami loses.
WOMEN WHO LOVE AND HATE
CAGE FOR CATS
There's an animal cage in front of you.
How many cats are in the cage?
What kind of abstract question is that?
CHIKA FUJIWARA
WANTS TO TEST YOU
It's a psychological test!
It's from a book
I borrowed from the library.
Just by answering this question,
I'll be able to understand
the depths of your mind, President.
That's silly.
As if you could understand the workings
of the mind with a question like that.
Come on, just humor me.
How many cats?
I guess about nine cats.
That tells me
how many children you want!
That's exactly right!
Nine kids? That's like a baseball team!
Nine kids? That many?
PSYCHOLOGY TEST
Psychology tests.
Abstract questions that draw out
what someone really thinks.
Most of them have amusing game elements
that employ the Barnum effect,
but some of them are practical
and based on actual psychology.
The person who thinks of these tests
only as an amusing trifle
and lets their guard down
may be in for a bitter experience.
I've got another really interesting one!
Let's do it together!
Oh, us, too?
Yes!
Are you ready?
"You're walking down a dark path.
Suddenly, someone taps you
on the shoulder from behind.
Who is that person?"
Give me a hint.
This isn't a quiz,
so it doesn't work that way.
Oh.
A dark path...
What could this be getting at?
There it is!
The second question on page 47!
That answer...
THAT'S THE PERSON YOU'RE IN LOVE WITH!!
indicates whom you're in love with!
If you say the name
of someone of the opposite sex
it's like a confession of love!
As is often the case,
Kaguya had prepared for this situation.
PLEASE TYPE IN A NAME
CHIKA FUJIWARA'S BRAIN
Kaguya has known Chika Fujiwara
since middle school
and is especially familiar
with her behavioral patterns.
CHIKA'S BRAIN
LOVE, PLAYING, EATING, PESU
Ever since Kaguya noticed
the book was on the library's list of purchases,
she predicted a high likelihood of Fujiwara
bringing it to the student council room.
PSYCHOLOGY TESTS FOR LOVE
Kaguya read the book in advance!
"Question. You bring a squirrel home.
She's able to avoid any dangerous answers.
What do you do with it then?"
Let's see. I would make
delicious food for it every day...
and give it a massage
before it went to sleep.
The answer is...
"After you get married,
what will you do for your spouse?"
In other words,
by being able to negotiate this minefield
called a "psychological test,"
she holds a huge advantage.
Let me think.
It would be you, Miss Fujiwara.
M-Me?
BASHFUL BASHFUL
A dark path...
Why are you running away, Ishigami?
My answer is Shinomiya-senpai.
Me?
That's how Ishigami feels?
He's a nice boy, and I don't dislike him...
but I'm sorry.
Ishigami is on the level of a worm to me.
Ishigami is rejected.
Now the president is the real issue.
I hate dark, scary places.
President, let's go home together.
Well, I—
Grin!
Wait! Why is Fujiwara
grinning at me like that?
GRIN GRIN
She called it "really interesting."
A question
that love-obsessed girl pounced on...
This one is definitely not a harmless test!
If the answer is
"The person you're in love with..."
Oh, President...
So, you're subconsciously
in love with me?
How cute.
It would be like a confession of love!
The best answer would be someone they'd be
satisfied with, but nobody in this room!
Then...
I guess my little sister.
"The person who taps you on the shoulder
indicates the person you're in love with."
In short, the president
has a sister complex.
That's the most boring answer.
That's right. I have a sister complex.
I'm in love with Shinomiya-senpai?
No, I think this emotion is terror!
President, I think I have
Stockholm syndrome, so I'm going home.
A-All right. Get well soon.
It could also be
the suspension bridge effect.
I'll go to a hospital on the way home.
I wanna try answering one myself,
so I'll look on the net.
Shoot! Miss Fujiwara is looking
for a question outside of the book!
This one's cute!
"You're in a field of flowers.
The owner said you can take home
as many flowers as you like.
How many will you take home?"
A question she doesn't know the answer to!
Flowers, huh?
I'd carefully pick only the prettiest ones.
So just a couple.
I-I suppose I'd take enough
to make a lovely bouquet.
I see.
What should I do?
I answered honestly without thinking!
How many for you, President?
Well, unlike that last one,
I don't have to say a name,
so I can answer it normally.
I can take as many as I like
for free, right?
Then there's only one possible answer.
HEAP
I'd take as many
as I could cram into a truck!
Maybe even a truck wouldn't be enough.
That's a poor person's mentality.
What would you do
with all of those flowers?
Well, I could give some away
and sell some, right?
Um, the answer is...
CLICK HERE FOR THE ANSWER
THE AMOUNT OF FLOWERS YOU TOOK INDICATES
HOW MUCH LOVE YOU HAVE FOR A SPECIAL SOMEONE!
What was the answer?
Nothing. Um, "How much
you love flowers" or something.
Yes, that's what it was.
Even though I love flowers?
Silly.
I don't agree with that one!
Neither do I.
But that's what the answer was.
We just have to accept it.
REASON:
HAVING A TRUCK
FULL OF LOVE
Results of today's match...
Shirogane loses.
I guess you're right.
COST OF A FAMILY
UM, IF YOU GET A HCG INJECTION,
THERE'S A 20% HIGHER CHANCE
OF GIVING BIRTH TO TWINS...
AH... HUH...
Wanna get a smoothie on the way home?
Okay!
- I'm gonna get celery!
- What kind should I get?
I'm totally sorry.
I'm working again today.
I have to go straight there.
Again?
You work too much.
Next time, definitely!
Yeah, okay!
It's time to go home, Lady Kaguya.
Hayasaka, I told you not to come
to the student council room.
I've confirmed that the president
and the other members have already left.
KAGUYA WANTS
TO BE NOTICED
Rest assured.
Carelessness like that can be fatal.
Recently, you've become lax, haven't you?
Between your appearance,
those nails,
UNBUTTONED
HER
COLLAR
NAILS
MYSTERIOUS
KEYCHAIN
and your skirt length,
you're likely violating school rules.
ROLLED UP HER SKIRT
It's all within the bounds
of school regulations.
Although you could say
I'm bending the rules a bit.
A bit.
For us, beauty is power.
BEAUTY IS LIVE AMMO
High society is not for people
without adornment.
You don't want opportunities stolen by women
with only good looks going for them.
I would say you're too stuffy about it,
Lady Kaguya.
Lately, lightly polished nails
are even in style here.
If you want men to think you're cute,
you should take an interest.
Really? Then will the president...
I mean, will boys think I'm cute?
After all this time, I'm surprised
you haven't given yourself away.
But, yes, of course.
Hayasaka realized that nails had little to do
with popularity amongst the opposite sex.
Boys will...
Come on. Let's go home and paint your nails.
But she gave only vague answers
in her desire to give Kaguya some glam.
Are you sure about this?
It's okay.
What's okay? Hey!
THE NEXT DAY
Gel nails which don't infringe
on the school dress code.
The modesty of rhinestone only
on each ring finger was part of the appeal.
I wonder what the president will think.
Will he think it's cute?
Or maybe he'll think it's frivolous.
What's the nail polish about?
I know.
I don't want it in that case.
I'll just go home today, and...
What are you doing, Shinomiya?
Aren't you going in?
Well, I was on my way in!
Miss Kaguya!
About this part...
Yes, what is it?
Are you hiding something behind you?
No, nothing.
The only times she's quick on the uptake
are situations like this!
If someone's going to notice,
I want it to be the president.
Certainly not her!
I have to get closer.
Here, President.
The minutes from our last meeting.
Oh, thanks.
Stare.
And there's an error here.
You're right.
Indeed.
Good eye!
He didn't notice!
Shinomiya is being fashionable!
Jeez, why?
Is it because you're not interested in me?
What caused the change?
She's always avoided ornamentation,
saying, "Does a swan dress up?"
What should I do?
Should I mention it?
You have nice childbearing hips.
Wouldn't that actually
be sexual harassment if I did?
LITTLE SISTER
Like the other day...
Kei, isn't that skirt too short?
I'm not wearing this for you.
That's sexual harassment. Drop dead.
I was just worried about her
as a big brother!
If there's a reaction from a person
other than the person you want,
it's sexual harassment.
But since I did notice,
I should say something, right?
I'm sure she won't be any crueler to me
than my little sister was!
Fujiwara-senpai...
You changed your conditioner, didn't you?
You can tell?
Yeah, well...
the smell is different than usual.
I mean, it is stuffy in here today,
but it's cute that the smell
is stronger than usual.
It kind of smells like a baby.
Ishigami...
That's creepy!
Let me die.
I want to die, so I'm going home.
S-Sure. But don't die.
It smelled good,
so I meant to give her a compliment.
Do I smell? Am I stinky?
That's tough!
The day Shinomiya calls me creepy,
I'm likely to choose death myself!
SNIFF SNIFF
I'd better not bring up her nails!
It's just too risky!
I can't risk having her call me "creepy"!
Wait. Is that just an excuse?
This is my issue.
Complimenting Shinomiya's nails...
I'm just genuinely bashful.
In the end, he didn't notice my nails.
But it's probably better that way.
It's meaningless for me
to be fashion-conscious.
It doesn't make me cute.
Shinomiya!
Those nails!
C-C-C-C-Cu...
Never mind! Nothing!
What?
Finish what you were going to say!
The president is cute
when he's all flustered, isn't he?
Jeez! Jeez!
You, too, Kaguya.
I-I wonder what he was about to say!
What do you think, Hayasaka?
"Hayasaka," I said!
He said, "Those nails!"
RESULTS OF TODAY'S MATCH:
KAGUYA WINS
Results of today's match...
Come on, Hayasaka!
Kaguya wins.