The god of thunder
will steal my belly button!
KAGUYA WANTS TO GIVE A GIFT
You're that afraid of thunder?
After all, it suddenly goes crack
and then boom!
I hate loud noises!
Then why not cover your ears?
If I cover my ears, then my hands
aren't free to protect my belly button!
I'd think that'd be obvious! I'd think
that'd be obvious! I'd think that'd be obvious!
What does "obvious" mean again?
Obvious.
I'm protecting my belly button,
so please cover my ears, Miss Kaguya.
S-Sure.
OBVIOUS
The trains are stopped
because of the typhoon!
That's a pain. You'd better call home.
We don't have a car,
so there's nothing they can do about it.
What am I gonna do?
That's right.
I can just give him a lift home.
SHUCHIIN ACADEMY
(MINATO WARD)
SHIROGANE'S HOUSE
(SETAGAYA WARD)
President, if you like...
Huh? That'd make it a driving date!
Going for a drive!
That is definitely a kind of date.
Sitting shoulder to shoulder
in an enclosed space,
listening to pleasant music on the radio
and chatting while cruising
through town in the rain.
And at red lights...
I wish this light
would never change to green.
...is the kind of thing they would think.
Strictly speaking, the presence of Kaguya's
driver would mean the two weren't alone,
but basically, to her, it would be
a prime example of a driving date.
Thus...
Ow! That hurts!
It's like I'm asking him out on a date!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
What's wrong, Shinomiya?
Nothing.
It's nothing.
If the president brought it up,
that's one thing,
but I can't afford to make the offer.
And yet,
abandoning him to his own devices
when he has no way to get home would be...
That's it! There's no problem
if he just says, "Give me a ride."
My taxi is almost here.
Oh, really?
What should I do?
Huh?
The president doesn't have a ride home?
L-Looks like it.
Then why don't we share the—
I just saw a flash of lightning.
I'll cover your ears tight
so you don't hear the thunder.
Thank you.
I'll cover your eyes, too, while I'm at it.
Why?
Now, I'll escort you to your taxi like this.
Wait!
Miss Kaguya!
I'm scared! I'm scared!
But it's kind of fun!
What kind of game is that?
With the element of chaos out of the way,
no one's left to interfere.
But how can I get him to say,
"Give me a ride"?
Crap, I have to work today.
At this rate, I'll miss my shift.
Indeed.
Taking off work because of a typhoon
would disqualify one
as a member of society.
Paying a taxi fare to get there
even though it'd cost more than daily wages,
or someone giving them a ride...
To a member of society,
the choice would be clear, you know?
That was effective.
I'm going to the restroom
and will think along the way!
Go right ahead.
It's hard to imagine the president
taking a taxi, cheapskate that he is.
So, naturally,
he'll come groveling to me.
IT'D PROBABLY BE AROUND 5,000 YEN...
I have this victory in the bag.
5,000 yen.
I make 1,000 an hour,
so that's five hours of work.
But I'd hate to miss it.
TRAIN OPERATING
TRAIN DELAYED
Huh? The trains
are running again!
Why now, of all times?
Pour it on a little harder, typhoon!
This leaves me no choice.
THE SEVEN ANTI-SHIROGANE TOOLS
TOOL ONE
RECHARGEABLE
BATTERY IS DEAD
Number one of the Seven
Anti-Shirogane Tools!
A dead battery!
Anticipating a variety of situations,
Kaguya has prepared a number of items
to take down Shirogane.
This dead rechargeable battery
is one of them!
I have about a minute before the president
returns from the restroom. During that time,
I'll switch out his phone battery!
There isn't much time.
Level of difficulty is very hard.
But I have confidence in myself!
What's the matter, Shinomiya?
N-Nothing. I was just doing
a little light exercise.
My battery's dead?
Hey, Shinomiya, can I borrow—
L-Looks like my ride's here, too,
so I'd better get going!
R-Right.
See you tomorrow.
Now I just need to wait here.
Shinomiya, you're getting a ride home?
Please! Give me a ride!
Well, I can hardly refuse
if you're reduced to begging me.
Poor President, I'll give you a lift home.
You're a goddess!
Um, Lady Kaguya, it's a cute scheme,
but if it works,
how am I supposed to get home?
On foot.
Are you a demon?
If you don't take better care of me,
karma will take a bite
out of your ass one day.
Oh, you and your karma...
See?
I was kidding.
I already called a taxi
for you, Hayasaka.
Jeez!
Well,
I figured this would happen, too.
Then, you should've stopped me before.
I'll take off school today, too.
I'll go make you some porridge.
No, stay by my side, Hayasaka.
I wish you were always this adorable.
Apparently, Shinomiya has a cold.
This will continue
in the Heart-pounding Visit chapter.
Very nice. I love how you can do
so many things with it!
SHIROGANE GOT A NEW BATTERY
FOR HIS (USED, NO WARRANTY) PHONE
Apparently, Shinomiya has a cold.
So, somebody's supposed to deliver
handouts to her house.
CHIKA FUJIWARA
WANTS TO PAY A VISIT
Me! I'll go!
Fujiwara?
I've visited her at home
when she was sick once before,
and it's hilarious how much of a baby
Miss Kaguya becomes when she has a cold!
GRIN
A baby?
President, dry my back.
She's so cute!
GLOW GLOW
It's the one time you can snatch her up
in a bear hug and she won't get angry!
President, I need a hug.
It wouldn't be fair if one person
got to monopolize her on her sickbed.
So let's all go together!
All?
Yes!
Wouldn't a crowd barging in on a sick person
show lack of common sense?
I think one person would be plenty.
TERRIFIED
I don't wanna go because I'm scared.
Good point.
Then, who'll go?
Let's play Concentration to decide!
CONCENTRATION
Concentration!
Needless to say,
a game that needs no introduction.
We won't use the jokers.
And if anyone's caught cheating,
they get minus five points.
We'll see who's first
with rock-paper-scissors.
All right, we'll start with the president!
Then, let's begin!
Hold your horses, Fujiwara!
Wh-Wh-What is it, President?
There are a number of points
I'm not clear about.
First, the fact that you challenged us
to a memory game.
I don't quite get that.
Normally, I'd think you'd choose
a game you were actually good at.
And you breezed through this rule,
but minus five points for cheating?
Not instant disqualification?
That made me wary.
I may not have noticed
if you'd kept your mouth shut,
but these designs
kinda look like numbers.
This is a marked deck!
It really is!
Fujiwara-senpai, that's low! Underhanded!
And getting caught
by the gambit you relied on!
That's the most embarrassing thing!
I'm embarrassed for you!
I'm going home!
Shame, shame, shame, shame,
shame, shame, shame, shame...
That's enough, Ishigami.
We accepted her rule about cheating
which this surely would've fallen under.
We only touched the deck, so we're fine.
That's right! It's only cheating
if you get caught! Nyah!
No, you certainly got caught.
Getting back on track...
In the first half of the game,
these flawed, but talented students
remembered the position of each card.
As the game proceeded,
they earned points, making no mistakes.
Shirogane, 10 points.
Fujiwara, 8 points. Ishigami, 10 points.
There were 24 cards left.
Now I'm tied with you, Ishigami.
President, wipe my front, too.
You guys have really good memories.
I'm gonna raise the bar a bit!
What?
Mixing them up!
An extremely annoying strategy to destroy
their memories of the cards' positions.
MIXING THE CARDS
Crap! I can't remember which is which!
After moving the cards around,
Fujiwara smoothly won several points,
even making up
for the penalty for cheating!
Let's enjoy the rest of the game, you guys!
Uh-oh. I'm in last place!
SHIROGANE: 10
FUJIWARA: 18 (-5)
ISHIGAMI: 12
CARDS REMAINING: 12
At this rate, I won't be able to see
Shinomiya acting like a baby!
President, pet my head.
What should I bring her?
She almost never gets sick,
so this is a rare opportunity!
Well, I'm not surprised she got a cold
after being drenched like that.
Shinomiya got drenched?
She got a ride home, didn't she?
Beats me. I just know
what I happened to see.
She was in front of the school gate
waiting for someone, I suppose.
Maybe...
she was waiting for me?
There's no definite proof.
If it was me...
Then, never mind
Shinomiya acting like a baby.
I'm an idiot for thinking
about nothing but silly things!
I'm the one who needs
to visit her at home!
Use your head for something
other than fantasizing about nonsense!
13.
13! Damn it! The matching card
appeared a minute ago!
Is she gonna get this one, too?
Nope.
Was it just a mistake?
No, wait.
I see.
It's your turn, President!
I got it!
SHIROGANE: 10
SHIROGANE: 12
I got it!
SHIROGANE: 14
SHIROGANE: 16
SHIROGANE: 18
I win.
FINAL SCORE:
1ST PLACE - SHIROGANE: 18
2ND PLACE - FUJIWARA: 18 (-5)
3RD PLACE - ISHIGAMI: 16
Shirogane took first place.
That was some comeback.
Well, if you know the trick, it's a cinch.
Trick?
The unusual thing about these cards
is that the patterns aren't symmetrical,
so you can use them like this.
I see!
The hands on a clock!
That's right.
By placing the cards at an angle,
you can reveal their face values
from 1 to 12.
So, Fujiwara wanted to place
the 13 cards far away
since they didn't figure into her plan.
Moving the cards around
was also done to hide her trick.
Fujiwara-senpai...
That's low!
Underhanded! Playing dirty!
You haven't learned your lesson at all!
You're shameless!
How did you get to be so shameless?
The most shameful thing is how he won
by finding your method and using it himself!
For shame!
Again, shame on you, Fujiwara-senpai!
Don't look at me!
A-After all... After all...
I just wanted to visit her at home!
I wanna die, so I'm going home.
Is that right?
But please don't die on us!
Even though it worked on my sisters...
Can you believe her brass?
This just goes to show
how shallow analog gamers are!
It's like she dug herself into a hole!
This happens when you do something
that doesn't suit you.
Shinomiya wouldn't have gotten
tripped up like that.
Shinomiya would have...
Crap! Now I'm nervous!
What should I bring her?
I wanna eat canned peaches, Hayasaka.
Yes, yes.
The Heart-pounding Visit
continues to Part Two.
WHAT DO YOU GIVE A RICH PERSON?
RESULTS OF TODAY'S MATCH:
FAILURE
SINCE NEITHER OF THEM
HAD A STRATEGY
This is the famous Shinomiya Villa!
I saw it online before,
but up close, it's amazing!
Maybe I should've done more
than bring drinks and jello.
I have been appointed to the role
of Lady Kaguya's caretaker.
My name is Smithee A. Herthaka.
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
COLOR CONTACTS
STUFFED A BIT
A maid!
I assume you have come
to visit Lady Kaguya.
ABOUT KAGUYA SHINOMIYA,
PART 1
Yes, exactly!
Then, I'll show you to her room.
Um, actually...
I'm only here
to deliver handouts to Shinomiya!
I was thinking you could
give it to her, Miss Herthaka!
Don't chicken out after coming this far.
Right this way.
Yes, but...
Honestly, I think it would be best
if you gave it to Lady Kaguya directly.
But...
Lady Kaguya...
you have a visitor.
Hey! What are you doing, Lady Kaguya?
Messy!
But I can't find them.
What are you looking for?
Fireworks.
Fireworks?
You'll do them with me,
won't you, Hayasaka?
I certainly will not.
Summer is around the corner.
I can understand why you'd jump the gun.
Your priority is to recover from this cold.
Meanie! I wanna do fireworks!
That aside, you have a visitor.
A visitor?
President!
What are you doing here, President?
Well, um...
Are you living here from now on?
I didn't hear about that!
No! I'm not moving in!
Miss Herthaka, what's wrong with her?
According to Sigmund Freud,
human actions are determined
by one's desire, the id,
ID (DESIRE)
and one's reason, the ego.
EGO (REASON)
I WANT TO SLEEP
Human instincts produce
the desires of the id
I WANT TO PUNCH
while it's the duty of the ego to act
as a brake that suppresses those desires.
I WANT TO EAT
I WANT TO PLAY
However, if the ability to think,
which is the source of the ego,
is lost for some reason,
the person becomes a beast
that acts according to the id.
In other words,
the person becomes a simpleton.
A simpleton?
And for people whose brains
are normally in full gear,
the effect is markedly pronounced.
At a glance, it looks like she's awake,
but she's actually in the middle
of a fever dream.
Once she's on her feet,
she'll have no memory at all
of the time she was sick.
It's as if she were drunk.
This is getting strange again.
Well, I need to get back to work,
so please keep Lady Kaguya company.
Understood.
Listen, I can assure you no one will enter
this room during the next three hours,
but you mustn't do anything inappropriate.
I-I won't.
On top of that,
this room is soundproofed,
and Lady Kaguya will have
no recollection of your visit.
So no matter what you do,
no one will be the wiser,
but absolutely...
do not do anything inappropriate.
I said I wouldn't!
Shinomiya, I bought you
a variety of drinks.
Want one?
Fireworks?
No, they're not fireworks.
It's useless.
Shinomiya isn't even in a state
to have a conversation.
If I'm honest with myself, my filthy mind
was hoping I could help her drink it,
but she's much weaker
than I anticipated.
If I take advantage of this,
I might be able to get Shinomiya's
true feelings and weaknesses out of her.
However...
Shinomiya, is it my fault
you caught this cold?
You intended to give me a ride
yesterday, didn't you?
And you were waiting
at the school gate, which is when...
I don't know.
I kinda feel like that's right,
and I kinda feel like that's wrong.
Well, which is it?
President, are you mad?
I'm sorry.
No, you didn't say anything
to make me mad.
No.
I'm always doing things
that make trouble for you.
I never know what to do.
For so many things,
it's the first time for me,
so I don't know.
IF YOU ARE A SHINOMIYA,
DO NOT RELY ON ANYONE. INSTEAD, USE THEM.
DO NOT RECEIVE ANYTHING. INSTEAD, STEAL.
DO NOT LOVE ANYONE. THERE IS NO INSTEAD.
So,
all I can do is behave the way I know how.
I don't know any other ways.
This is the only way I can do it.
So, for today...
let's sleep together.
No, Shinomiya!
Are you shy?
How cute.
Wait a second!
Shinomiya will forget this, too,
and no one will come into the room?
This situation
is just too convenient!
And I'm not confident
that I can control myself!
What the hell...
has happened to me?
ID AND EGO
SLEEP DEPRIVED
What time is it?
Feels like I've just come out of hibernation.
President?
What were you doing in my bed?
I-I just came over to visit you!
What kinda man takes the opportunity
to crawl into bed? Unbelievable!
You invited me!
In your dreams! How could you
do it when I was sleeping!
You're scum!
Get out of here right now!
Oh, dear. I thought
something like this might happen.
But it looks like you're well rested anyway.
H-Hayasaka,
how far did I go with the president?
I couldn't say.
Even after...
Even after I totally held back!
I held back for all I was worth!
The Heart-pounding Visit: The End.
Well, I guess nothing happened.