Carnage!
In Hindu mythology,
it indicates the location of the battle
of Asura demigods and the King of Heaven,
but at present, it's mainly used
to mean two other things.
The first is crunch time
right before a deadline.
And the other...
RUMBLE RUMBLE
is a scene of difficulties
between two people!
Please eat it.
Give me a break. You eat it, Shinomiya.
KAGUYA WON'T FORGIVE
It's my fault.
If I hadn't eaten any...
Explaining this situation requires
two incidents to be touched on.
THE FIRST INCIDENT:
"THE KAGUYA HOME VISIT INCIDENT"
Kaguya was out of it with a fever
when she pulled Shirogane into her bed.
SCOOP: KAGUYA HOME
VISIT INCIDENT
THE CARETAKER
WAS WATCHING!!
As a result, they slept next to each other
for hours and nothing more,
but when Kaguya came to her senses,
she was justifiably bewildered
and flew into a rage.
However, an on-the-scene inspection
proved Shirogane innocent for the time being,
and they handled it like adults.
I apologize for yelling at you.
No, it's my fault.
They reconciled, but...
there was still ill will!
In Kaguya's point of view,
he took advantage of her when she was
weakened with a cold, sharing her bed.
Maybe he touched her
when she was sleeping?
It made her feel uneasy.
And if he didn't do anything,
that ticked her off, too!
It made her feel dissatisfied.
But as for Shirogane,
he had a bone to pick, too.
He was the one
dragged into Shinomiya's bed,
and not only did she not understand
a man's hardship
of exerting every iota of self-restraint,
barely holding on,
but she also continued
to view him with suspicion.
So, it was only natural that he harbor
some resentment toward her.
These feelings of discontent would continue
to mount, leading to an inevitable blowup.
THE SECOND INCIDENT:
"THE CAKE INCIDENT"!
EARLIER
What's this?
It's from the headmaster.
Help yourself.
Yay!
This is all the cake there is?
I wish the headmaster
were more considerate.
He should've at least given us
enough for all the members.
Well, earlier, you and I
were the only ones here, President, so...
Don't worry. Eat up, Ishigami.
I don't need any.
No, please have it, President.
Don't mind me.
It's okay. You eat it, Shinomiya.
No, no, you, President.
No, really, go ahead.
No, I insist.
I insist!
No, I insist!
Just eat it already!
You should eat it, President!
Discontent. This is where it blows up!
ONE MINUTE LATER
Girls like this kind of thing,
so don't hold back.
You don't have an aversion to sweets,
do you, President? So, please.
Essentially polite,
willing to give up their share.
Look, while you're arguing,
it's getting mushy.
FIVE MINUTES LATER
But as the minutes passed,
it entered into a new phase.
Yes, right.
And it's almost time to go home.
I'm a slow eater,
so by all means, President.
My hand's already getting tired
from holding this plate!
20 MINUTES LATER
If you eat it, this whole issue
would be settled peacefully, right?
You're so stubborn.
ONE HOUR LATER
Would you just eat it, already?
There's no need for you
to be so obstinate here, President.
After an hour of this, no one would object
to it being called "a scene of carnage."
The place had turned into
an underworld of mingled resentment!
The cake wants you
to eat it, too, President!
It's my fault.
If I hadn't eaten a piece,
this never would've happened.
Use common sense when you speak!
Cake can't talk!
Prove to me that cake can't talk!
This has become a disaster.
Extraordinary claims
require extraordinary proof!
I've got it!
Fujiwara-senpai!
Fujiwara-senpai is the only one
who can stop those two!
Why are you being so pigheaded
about not eating it?
There's a limit
to how stubborn one can be!
Yes, I admit to being stubborn!
But it's because of something
you said before, Shinomiya!
Just what did I say?
It was right after we both started
in the student council!
Do you have any hobbies, Shinomiya?
No, but is that any of your business?
Not really.
It's just that your eyes are so lifeless.
I was wondering
if there was anything that you liked.
Something I like...
Shortcake.
That's what you said!
I could never forget that face!
Why would you remember
something so trivial from that long ago?
How could I forget?
Is that right? Is that right?
The tip of my nose itches!
I'm going to scratch!
Don't mind me!
Sure, scratch all you like!
He remembered from that long ago.
If that's your story,
then I've got one, too!
What?
The end of last year!
What are you going to do
for Christmas, President?
Work.
Oh, really?
That's tough.
Not especially.
To me, Christmas is just another day.
My old man gives me a gift certificate
for 2,000 yen worth of books. That's it.
We don't really celebrate,
and I've never had Christmas cake.
Not that I'm envious or anything.
Hearing that made me kind of sad!
You've never been able to have it before,
so I want you to eat this cake, President!
You remember that?
Is that right? Is that right?
Actually, my forehead itches!
Never mind me while I scratch it!
Scratch away! I don't care!
Enough!
Since it's come to this, I have an idea!
For today only, I'll feed you!
No, just the opposite!
I'll feed you, Shinomiya!
Please don't steal my feeding idea!
Don't be shy! Just open your mouth!
You open your mouth, Shinomiya!
- Open wide!
This isn't getting us anywhere!
You have a bite, and then I'll have a bite!
No, you go first! If you eat it, I'll eat it!
No complaints if we eat
at the same time?
That's fine!
GRR GRR
Here I go!
This is the Friend Police!
Are you the naughty kids
who've been fighting?
NO FIGHTING!
IF YOU CAN'T GET ALONG,
I'LL CONFISCATE YOUR CAKE!
Results of today's match...
RESULTS OF TODAY'S MATCH:
Kaguya and Shirogane lose.
KAGUYA AND SHIROGANE LOSE
WAR CRIMINAL
MMM, YUMMY
Romantic advice?
Well, it's not really romantic, but...
KAGUYA WANTS TO FORGIVE
advice about the opposite sex.
Um, like a good way to make up with someone
of the opposite sex you had a fight with.
Since you have a boyfriend,
Miss Kashiwagi,
I thought maybe you'd have
some useful advice.
Seriously?
You're asking me for romantic advice?
Well, not exactly romantic,
I want to see if you know a way
to make peace with someone
of the opposite sex you had a fight with.
I see. In that case,
you've come to the right person.
I'm the Love Master.
Seriously?
I'm kidding.
You're kidding?
But I do read a lot of romcom manga.
I guess that would work.
I'm asking for a friend.
When you put it like that,
it sounds like you're talking
about yourself, President.
But you wouldn't be that clichéd,
would you?
Yeah, right, as if.
So...
So, Miss Shinomiya, what were you
and this person fighting about?
Well...
By the way, I'm asking for a friend.
It's not me.
This is definitely about Miss Shinomiya.
A friend of mine, a girl,
came down with a cold,
and then, a boy visited her at home.
But while she was delirious
with a fever...
Um...
I guess you could say they slept together.
When she woke up,
the boy was in bed next to her.
That's terrible! Shameless!
What a brute!
Of course...
nothing happened!
In fact, the girl was so out of it
that it's possible she initiated...
Even so!
It's especially when a girl
is in a weakened state
that the man must have morals
and not do anything!
I agree. That's the correct way
to see it, right?
That boy doesn't have any morals, right?
Right? Right? Right? Right?
RIGHT!?
What's wrong with that girl?
She sounds like a lunatic!
What kind of woman invites you into her bed,
then berates you the next morning?
Sounds like she's got no morals.
That woman sounds like
a real pain in the ass.
In a romcom, she'd be the standard
black-haired, flat-chested type.
Typical, typical.
Incredible. Once he gets going,
he doesn't stop.
Being loopy with a fever is no excuse.
I mean, she pulled a dude into bed.
Bet you anything she's a nympho.
At a glance, she's prim and proper,
not to mention stuck-up.
The way she expresses
her sexual desire is twisted, selfish!
She says, "I'm not interested in men,"
but with a handsome guy,
she'll get her teeth into him
in no time!
If a man is a wolf,
then, a woman's a snake.
Quick to get entangled
and swallows the tail.
Ouroboros, I'm telling you!
Not me! Not this cat!
I'm sure after the guy left, she rubbed—
Okay, hit the brakes, Ishigami.
Look, even so, the guy really
shouldn't have gone along with it.
There had to be a gentle way
of getting out of it, but he just didn't do it.
No.
He probably didn't want to get out of it.
- Fight!
- Yeah!
But they apologized to each other
about it, so it's settled.
The thing is, after that, the boy acted
totally normal as if nothing had happened.
I feel you.
The girl is like on pins and needles,
while the guy has already moved on...
when it wasn't just some minor mishap.
Exactly!
So, it's only natural for her
to be a little annoyed with him, right?
Of course!
In the first place,
they were in the same bed,
so the man should take responsibility
and tell her how he feels about her!
Th-That's right!
He's being too irresponsible, right?
Right? Right? Right?
Shut up, you moron!
They apologized to each other, right?
Then, it should be over and done with!
Why the hell is she dragging it out?
He's so loud.
Just hearing that pisses me off!
How about if I give
that woman a talking-to?
I'll tell her what time it is!
But...
that's fine as it is.
She doesn't want him
to take responsibility or anything.
Then, what's to be angry about?
What's to be... angry about?
If he didn't lay a finger on you and you
don't want him to take responsibility...
then, what's to be angry about,
Miss Shinomiya?
I can't say.
I just can't say it!
That I actually wanted him
to do something, just a little!
I'm sorry.
Am I really that unappealing?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
I can't tell her I'm angry
about something that silly!
Of course I can't tell anyone about that!
That? Th-Th-That?
That's how a guy should be like when
a woman is pissed about some trivial thing.
Anyway, for a man to try to understand
everything about a woman,
it's probably just a fool's errand.
In the end, your friend
should just chill out until the heat's off.
If he doesn't have anything
to feel guilty about,
then there's no need for him to apologize.
Nothing to feel guilty about, huh?
Shinomiya, there's something
I have to tell you.
What is it?
I told you I didn't lay a finger on you,
but...
the truth is...
I did lay just one finger on you!
Where did you...
touch me?
Your lips.
I maybe just tapped them
with my pointer finger.
I mean, not in any weird sense
or like a prank or—
President...
Now we're even.
Starting tomorrow,
we'll be back to normal, right?
Y-Yeah.
Results of today's match...
RESULTS OF TODAY'S MATCH:
They both won.
THEY BOTH WON
(SUCCESSFULLY MADE UP)
PASSING BY
HUH...
Great work, student council!
And it's summer vacation
starting tomorrow!
- Yay!
RUSTLE RUSTLE
Do you have any special plans,
Shinomiya?
Go shopping a little is about all.
Will you be busy working, President?
Nope.
MIYUKI SHIROGANE
WANTS TO GO SOMEWHERE
When they adjusted the schedule,
they kind of short-sheeted me.
That leaves me
with a lot of time on my hands.
I'd like to do something.
Yes, I'd like to do something.
- Right, Fujiwara?
- Right, Miss Fujiwara?
SUMMER VACATION PLANS!!
Summer vacation plans!
- Mountains!
- Beach!
Mt. Osore!
The topic of a trip was discussed once
but ended up getting put off.
Will it come to nothing or be carried out?
The moment had come
to make that decision.
There are many events that take place
during summer vacation.
AUGUST
TRIP
FIREWORKS
SUMMER FESTIVAL
BBQ
BEACH
Whether a coed group
goes to these events together
all depends on whether
they get off to a good start.
By going somewhere together
for the first time...
"Where should we go next?"
"Let's all go somewhere again."
And that opens up possibilities.
On the other hand,
if they stumble at the start,
the psychological hurdle
for a coed plan becomes higher!
Boys will stick with the boys,
girls with the girls,
and that's how they'll spend
summer vacation.
If they fail here,
it'll be a gray summer vacation!
THE GIRL'S SANDAL BREAKS,
AND I MUST CARRY HER
No! No! No! No! No! No!
TEST OF COURAGE
GOING HOME
TO THE COUNTRY
AND SEEING YOUR
CHILDHOOD FRIEND
TIME LEAPS AND
DIFFERENT DIMENSION
SUMMONS
ONE-SUMMER
ADVENTURES
ARE SURELY
NOT POSSIBLE
DOING
HOMEWORK
TOGETHER
LOVEY-DOVEY
WORDS THAT GET
MUTED THROUGH
EXPLODING
FIREWORKS
GOING ON
COED TRIPS
TOGETHER
OH NO,
I NEED
TO DO CPR
FINDING LOVE
AT THE TEMP JOB
Nooo!
SWIMSUITS AND BBQ
AT THE BEACH
Reality!
That's what reality is!
A trip with Shinomiya?
Of course I wanna go!
But if I bring up the idea of a trip here...
Oh, President...
Are you bringing up that again?
That was like a one-shot topic. I mean,
it wasn't a serious conversation, right?
Are you really thinking of going?
Did you have your heart set on that?
How cute.
AAAH
That would happen!
Summer! Summer! Summer vacation!
You're the one who brought up a trip!
What are you doing just dancing around?
Summer vacation! Summer vacation!
Fujiwara!
Summer is the time...
when you wanna just go all out
and spread your wings, right?
DI... VERSION
Right! Summer is the time you wanna
do something you usually can't do!
Like a trip would be great!
Yeah, that's it!
A trip, huh?
Sure, everyone needs time away from
the hustle and bustle of life in the city, right?
Yes!
I'm going to Hawaii for about a week!
This is gonna work!
You can go to hell!
You're the one who said before
you wanted to go on a trip with everyone!
What's the idea of taking the lead
and acting like you're Hawaiian?
Aloha in Honolulu!
Shinomiya, she's your whatever,
isn't she? Do something!
Yes.
A trip... is a good idea.
Kaguya also understands the importance
of getting off to a good start
for summer vacation.
However, she's known Fujiwara
for a long time
and thus realizes there is no chance
that Fujiwara will behave to one's satisfaction.
Therefore, there is nothingness!
The empty mind that has checked out!
Breathing is fun.
NOTHING...
It's no use! I don't sense
any drive in Shinomiya!
W-Well, if Fujiwara is going on a trip,
that's all she wrote.
The idea of all of us going somewhere
on a trip was a tall order to begin with.
But at least...
At least go somewhere
on a day trip and have fun!
But...
Go somewhere without Miss Fujiwara?
In other words, you want to go somewhere
with me and not with Miss Fujiwara?
Oh my.
How cute.
I'm checkmated!
AAAH
Without Fujiwara,
it won't get off the ground!
Aloha! Honolulu!
Can she do something like a week
after she gets back from her trip?
Fujiwara...
A trip abroad is fine,
but so is a trip here, right?
There are a lot of events during summer.
What are you talking about?
SERIOUS SERIOUS
Second-year summer is crunch time
for university entrance exams!
I don't have time
to fritter away on having fun!
You asshole!
You'd say that when you're the one
who's going on a trip?
Exactly! I'm keeping a balance
between work and play!
Dammit! That's a fair argument!
President, don't bother.
You'll never be able to control Fujiwara.
At a time like this, I think about yummy food.
Crap! I planned to win
Shinomiya's heart this summer!
How cute.
Whatever pattern I attack,
that's how it ends up!
Is it a lost cause?
But I'd like to do something
to make memories, even just once.
Ishigami?
I'm a first-year,
and you're a second-year, President.
Maybe next year, with studying
for university entrance exams,
there won't be time for anything.
Maybe this is the only year we could hang out.
Ishigami...
This is what you've been thinking?
That's right. Summer isn't
just about hanging out with girls.
Having dumb fun with guy friends...
That's summer, too.
Let's go, Ishigami.
There's a big festival
at the end of summer.
I can treat you to takoyaki.
Summer festival?
Let's go! Let's go!
What happened to crunch time?
That's a great idea!
Cotton candy! The shooting game!
Fireworks!
Fireworks?
Fireworks with the president?
I'm in!
The festival is on August 24th, right?
I'll keep my schedule open.
Yes, me, too.
Wait. I can't make it. I'll be
in Spain then for the tomato festival.
Go to the festival in hell, idiot!
How many trips are you taking?
Oh no! Worldly desires! Worldly desires!
Her empty mind collapsed.
Don't tell me you're gonna go!
Well...
You guys would be so mean to go
to a summer festival without me?
Yeah, why not?
You're going to the tomato festival,
aren't you, Fujiwara-senpai?
You're gonna have fun there,
but telling us not to go? Give me a break.
WAAAAH
You're so mean to me, Ishigami!
Idiot! Cold-blooded human!
Your bangs are too long!
Ishigami, I hope you burn
your tongue on a takoyaki!
I did it again.
I'm going home.
Wait, Ishigami.
You were in the right today.
Results of today's match...
RESULTS OF TODAY'S MATCH:
Victory for everyone except for Fujiwara.
VICTORY FOR EVERYONE EXCEPT FOR FUJIWARA
(FOR SUCCESSFULLY MAKING A PLAN
TO GO TO THE SUMMER FESTIVAL)
Well, let's meet there on that day at 7 pm.
Yes, I'm looking forward to it.
And so, we embark on a new chapter!
Men and women's summer vacation!
OH NO
PADDED
I SEE...